<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>The Asocial</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://theasocial.com" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>The Asocial</name>
        <email>info@theasocial.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2016-10-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Human sleep modes</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/life/human-sleep-modes.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/life/human-sleep-modes.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info life">
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">The ways to mess up your sleep</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        October 12, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/life.html">life</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>Sleep is essential to human health and functioning. The need to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleep">sleep</a> is probably one of the most unpleasant things one has to deal with when they have stuff to do, yet the ability to sleep may be one of the most pleasant ones when they don’t. That’s why we take a look at the ways people manage (or mess up) their sleep.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Circadian_rhythm">circadian rhythm</a> is what entangles people into the sleep-wake cycle, the duration of which is usually roughly equal to the time it takes for Earth to complete a full rotation about its axis on average.</p>
<p>Before <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Control_of_fire_by_early_humans">control of fire</a><a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a><a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2"><sup>2</sup></a>, those cycles were all hyped: all the important stuff should have been done during daytime, and it was dark at night before that. Fire was — as they were calling it back then — rad, though people were still into hunting and gathering: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neolithic_Revolution">agricultural revolution</a> happened only around 12,500 years ago, and they didn’t have computers before that. Anyway, now one may have stuff to do all day long, but the rhythms are still there.</p>
<p>Whether naturally or by choice, many people do follow those rhythms, even despite <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insomnia">insomnia</a> and hard time waking up. But some opt for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-24-hour_sleep%E2%80%93wake_disorder">non-24-hour sleep-wake</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irregular_sleep%E2%80%93wake_rhythm">irregular sleep-wake</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biphasic_and_polyphasic_sleep">biphasic/polyphasic sleep</a>, or a combination of those.</p>
<p>In this article, we are going to investigate how various sleep modes affect human lives.</p>
<h2 id="non-24-hour-sleep-wake">Non-24-hour sleep-wake</h2>
<p>That’s a rare disorder that happens when you stop fighting insomnia and using an alarm. Well, at least that’s how it may work if you have <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delayed_sleep_phase_syndrome">DSPD</a> (there’s a rumor that some people don’t have it, so apparently they just go to bed and wake up early, without an alarm or anything). If the cycles are still regular, you still can plan things, just not for any daytime. It only screws regular fixed-time activities, such as an office job.</p>
<p>But let’s be realistic: such a regularity is not exactly what happens if your days are at least slightly different. Usually one day you may get tired more than usual and fall asleep earlier. The next day you may get excited or worried about something, having trouble to sleep, or simply stay longer to finish the stuff you were working on, and the day after that – have an event to attend at a fixed time, setting an alarm, and screwing even that regime. What brings us to the next mode.</p>
<h2 id="irregular-sleep-wake">Irregular sleep-wake</h2>
<p>Wikipedia says that it’s an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invisible_disability">invisible disability</a>, and that “[i]t can create social, familial, and work problems, making it hard for a person to maintain relationships and responsibilities, and may make a person home-bound and isolated”. Though it may be a problem, it’s not a big deal if you are already asocial, except for possible work problems that were already mentioned above.</p>
<p>Although it brings a bunch of other minor inconveniences. Let’s see what happens when you want to visit a regular store: it seems that you have 16 hours of wakefulness, and if the store works for 12 hours per day, there is at least a 4-hour overlap every day. Yet you may sleep up to 12 hours, being sleepy for the last few hours, and taking time to get past <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleep_inertia">sleep inertia</a> when you wake up, as well as to have a breakfast, take a shower, etc – what shrinks the convenient working time. A store may also not be that close to you, so one may add a hour to dress up and get there. All that combined may leave no overlap at all on an arbitrary picked day. Add other things you may want or have to do, and it gets inconvenient rather often: even if you get an overlap, it may not be the time you’d pick if there was a choice. While if you are awake during daytime, most of the time you are awake would work to visit that store.</p>
<p>It’s probably even worse if you order a delivery: since the most responsible people rarely end up being couriers, and delivery companies usually schedule delivery for a range of a few hours, you have to plan being awake for a few hours, possibly a few days ahead. That means that you should maintain at least some kind of a regime during those few days, or adjust the time on the day of delivery.</p>
<p>When you’re trying to adjust your regime to fit the plans, it may involve staying awake longer than you would like to, or trying to sleep when you don’t want to. Both are a waste of time, since you’re neither sleeping nor productive during that, and the latter is the same as one of the downsides of having a regime.</p>
<h2 id="biphasic-and-polyphasic-sleep">Biphasic and polyphasic sleep</h2>
<p>Those are fancy names for daily napping. Napping is generally nice: you may observe that cats do that rather often, and they know what’s good. Napping is common among other animals, too.</p>
<p>But biphasic/polyphasic sleep is more than just occasional napping: it is also called “segmented sleep” and “divided sleep”, implying that it’s about dividing your sleep into a few periods during a cycle.</p>
<p>A bunch of organizations, including NASA and U.S. military, researched the topic, since it’s a nice topic to research. Now there are napping guides, napping tips, napping experts, and napping professionals out there, according to a quick web search. It seems that it is even good for your <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Working_memory">working memory</a>, though it’s not clear how it affects you in a longer term.</p>
<p>Yet it may be quite practical when combined with irregular and non-24-hour sleep: it may be more easily adjustable than a 8-10-hour sleep, since you don’t normally have 16-20 hours without sleep behind you with it, yet the body should still be able to stay awake for those 16-20 hours rather easily. And let’s consider the store situation again: with two equidistant 4-5-hour naps every 24 hours, you get a guaranteed overlap of 7-8 hours, without any adjustment.</p>
<p>Without irregular and non-24-hour sleep, it may even be compatible with a daytime job: working, sleeping, doing other stuff, sleeping again, in a loop.</p>
<p>It may require some effort to get into this mode and to stay in it, since it’s rather easy to stay “late” for a whole day if you’re busy, then fall asleep for a long time, and then get trouble getting a nap after a few hours of being awake. But if you’re willing to put effort into its maintenance, it might be easier to just put that into maintaining a regular 24-hour regime.</p>
<h2 id="hypnotics-and-stimulants">Hypnotics and stimulants</h2>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypnotic">Hypnotics</a> (sleeping pills) and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stimulant">stimulants</a> (caffeine, amphetamine, cocaine, etc) may help to manage your sleep, though the most efficient ones are usually illegal, and even the legal ones have unpleasant side effects when abused.</p>
<h2 id="sleep-deprivation">Sleep deprivation</h2>
<p>According to Wikipedia, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleep_deprivation">sleep deprivation</a> has unpleasant consequences, so it’s not a nice way to get more of free time. Among other things, it may lead to a somewhat interesting condition of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsleep">microsleep</a>.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>It would be awesome to sleep when it’s convenient, and be awake when you have stuff to do. Alas, it’s not exactly how a human body works.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>About 400,000 years ago, when people looked a bit <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homo_erectus">more like monkeys</a> than they do now.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Or maybe even 2.3 million years ago – they’ve only got writing around 5,000 years ago, and started writing lies around that time as well, so it’s hard to know those things for sure.<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Peer review</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/peer-review.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/peer-review.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-08T18:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-08T18:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info comics">
  
  <img src="/images/comics/peer-review.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Reviews are hard</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        October  8, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/comics.html">comics</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Pimp My Code, issue 3</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/pimp-my-code-issue-3.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/pimp-my-code-issue-3.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-08T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/pimp-my-code.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Exabit and his team pimp an old LaTeX document class</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        October  8, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="pimp-my-code-issue-2.html">Previously</a> on <a href="https://github.com/pimp-my-code">Pimp My Code</a>: <a href="https://github.com/getlogbook/logbook">logbook</a>, a python logging library, <a href="https://github.com/getlogbook/logbook/pull/201">got logging of its own</a>, as well as new looks.</p>
<p>Today Exabit visits <a href="https://github.com/cambridge">University of Cambridge</a>, where <a href="https://github.com/cambridge/thesis/graphs/contributors">Matej and his friends</a> are struggling to get any PDFs out of <a href="https://github.com/cambridge/thesis">their old LaTeX document class</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: Yo. Everyone enjoys reading, and I’m reading with these smooth and grotesque <a href="http://dejavu-fonts.org/">DejaVu</a> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sans-serif">sans-serif</a> fonts, because I’m Exabit. Unfortunately for my man Matej, this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_Modern">Computer Modern</a>’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roman_%28typeface%29">Roman</a> font is no good for eyes. But not to worry: Matej has no idea, but we’re about to pimp his code.</p>
<p><em>Exabit knocks the door, the door opens.</em></p>
<p><strong>Matej</strong>: No way! You gotta be joking! No waay! Exabit!</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: Yeah, yeah, calm down. I’ve come here today, and I’m ready to pimp your code.</p>
<p><strong>Matej</strong>: I can’t believe it, is it really you?</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: It’s me, alright? So, what about your code? Do you have a name for it?</p>
<p><strong>Matej</strong>: It’s just called “thesis”, but informally we call it “embarrassment”.</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: Well, show me your “embarrassment”.</p>
<p><strong>Matej</strong>: Here it is. It’s a regular black-on-white model, though rather old one. The fonts got serifs with time, the typos are abundant. Obviously it has seen better days.</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: Oh wow. And what’s up with that Makefile?</p>
<p><strong>Matej</strong>: Well, it got circular dependencies, nobody knows how it works at all.</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: Okay, I’ve seen enough. I’m taking this off to our garage where we will end its suffering.</p>
<p><em>Exabit makes a few gangsta gestures, takes off from the third attempt. When he arrives to the garage, Victor and El Hackerozo appear to protest.</em></p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: Okay, check this out. This is a 2011 LaTeX document class. What can we do with this?</p>
<p><strong>Victor</strong>: A “screen” mode is a must. Since it’s a document class, we could simply add it as an option; then it would set fonts and colors for on-screen reading.</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: Sounds good, what else?</p>
<p><strong>El Hackerozo</strong>: There’s so much free space. I think we should hide empty pages in that “screen” mode, and add some flames on the title page. You know how pale some of those papers look like?</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: Yeah, yeah, they are like “we are so awesome that we don’t have to look nice”, but they actually have to, you know what I’m saying?</p>
<p><strong>El Hackerozo</strong>: I do. So, we can make a flame contour, which would simply stay that way in the print mode, but will be filled with screen mode.</p>
<p><strong>Victor</strong>: Somebody should also fix those typos.</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: Oh, guys, I forgot to show you: this Makefile has circular dependencies.</p>
<p><em>Victor grabs his head in horror.</em></p>
<p><strong>Victor</strong>: I’m not sure if we’ll have enough time to get rid of that, but I’ll take a look.</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: Well, sounds good, let’s do this!</p>
<p><em>The team works on it for hours, and it’s finally the time to present the work to the client. Matej and his friends are coming in, <a href="https://github.com/cambridge/thesis/pull/29">the team presents the work</a>:</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Yo dawg.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I heard you like LaTeX. So we’ve put more LaTeX into your LaTeX.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>But first things first. Remember that old Makefile of yours, that was failing to make a PDF after <code>make clean</code>? Guess what? We fixed it! That’s right, now it’s actually doing what it’s supposed to do.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Of course we’ve fixed a few typos here and there: even the samples of your new class file should be impeccable.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Now, let me show you something. See this new TikZ flame contour? It’s fancy even this way, but let’s turn on your brand new <code>screen</code> documentclass option. Not just it brings the flame to life, it sets the default font family to sans serif, skips the empty pages, and even updates the background color of every page! It was not healthy to read from a screen with the contrast as high as there was before, and just look at those smooth letters!</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Now that it’s easier on the eyes, you’ll always have a steady flow of new dissertations, since the students are gonna just love it. No lone nights with nothing to read anymore!</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>We’ve also found a hidden submission notice claiming that the thesis is badass, and restored it – no need to be humble with this beauty!</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Yo, look <a href="/exhaust/pimp-my-code-cambridge-thesis.pdf">here</a>. Yeah, that’s a new shield – not exactly of a college, but indicating that you’ve been officially pimped!</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s been our pleasure pimping your thesis template. See you next time!</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em><a href="https://dl.bintray.com/matej/cam-thesis/thesis.pdf">Before</a> and <a href="/exhaust/pimp-my-code-cambridge-thesis.pdf">after</a>.</em></p>
<p><strong>Matej</strong>: Whoa, sick visuals! Awesome typo fixes! And look at this Makefile, ahh. May I try it?</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: Of course, it’s all yours!</p>
<p><strong>Matej</strong>: Awesome, it works!</p>
<p><strong>Victor</strong>: Sure it does. Hey, let’s turn the screen mode on.</p>
<p><strong>Matej and friends</strong>: Wow, unbelievable! Thank you guys!</p>
<p><strong>Exabit</strong>: No problem, that’s what we do. It was Pimp My Code on The Asocial, see you next time!</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>systemd</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/systemd.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/systemd.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info computing">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/redhat.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">History and current state</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:RedHat.svg">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        October  6, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/computing.html">computing</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>Once upon a time, there was a guy named <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lennart_Poettering">Lennart Poettering</a>, who was involved into edgy projects such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PulseAudio">PulseAudio</a> (the monster sound server that runs on top of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Linux_Sound_Architecture">ALSA</a> driver, leading to half the sound problems – the other half is caused by ALSA) and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avahi_(software)">Avahi</a> (an implementation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multicast_DNS">mDNS</a> and related things – one of those programs that seem to rarely be used outside of corporate environments). The monstrosity of both is comparable to that of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D-Bus">D-Bus</a>, which is actually used by both. It shouldn’t be a surprise that Lennart currently works for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Hat">Red Hat</a> – a company responsible for things such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NetworkManager">NetworkManager</a> and other abominations.</p>
<p>Back in 2010, Lennart started working on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systemd">systemd</a>. There already was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Init#Replacements_for_init">a variety of init systems</a>, but the most widely used ones were rather messy: non-portable across systems shell scripts for daemons alone were quite a pain to deal with. In November 2010, systemd got into <a href="https://getfedora.org/">Fedora</a> (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux">RHEL</a> beta) repositories, and became default there in May 2011. Journald (its logging system) was <a href="http://blog.gerhards.net/2011/11/journald-and-rsyslog.html">criticized by rsyslog author</a> in 2011. In 2012, the Slackware author <a href="https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/interviews-28/interview-with-patrick-volkerding-of-slackware-949029/">claimed</a> that systemd violates <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_philosophy">UNIX philosophy</a>. By 2015, it already ate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Udev">udev</a>, implemented its much criticized logging system, a login shell, and grew a bunch of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systemd#Ancillary_components">other components</a>, for what it has been criticized – as well as for being Linux-specific, doing half-assed job, and so on. Yet, after a <a href="https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=727708">long</a> <a href="https://wiki.debian.org/Debate/initsystem">debate</a>, in April 2015 it became default in <a href="https://www.debian.org/">Debian</a>. There’s more of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systemd#History">systemd history</a>, which mostly consists of criticizm, in the Wikipedia article.</p>
<p>Though systemd finally made daemons easily portable across major Linux-based systems, it made them incompatible with other Unix-like systems, and with a few Linux-based ones that continued to resist – such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slackware">Slackware</a> and <a href="https://www.gentoo.org/">Gentoo</a>.</p>
<p>Somewhere along the way, we’ve got the “boycott systemd” campaign, a systemd-free Debian fork, and <a href="http://without-systemd.org">without-systemd.com wiki</a>. But that’s not all: now we’re getting things such as “<a href="https://www.agwa.name/blog/post/how_to_crash_systemd_in_one_tweet">How to Crash Systemd in One Tweet</a>” (the title is actually misleading and weird, but the article is rather interesting) and “<a href="http://suckless.org/sucks/systemd">systemd is the best example of Suck</a>” by <a href="http://suckless.org/">suckless.org</a>.</p>
<p>Systemd is not the first attempt to fix the init mess: “<a href="http://blog.darknedgy.net/technology/2015/09/05/0/">A history of modern init systems (1992-2015)</a>” gives a nice outline of those, with occasional config examples. Yet it’s the one that was backed by Red Hat, what contributed to both development and the wide adoption.</p>
<p>To be fair, Linux kernel itself is huge and monolithic, and the tools that were widely used before systemd are not much better. There’s the monstrous, often monolithic and bloated, often by Red Hat or GNOME and resembling MS Windows, “enterprise” junk with D-Bus and stuff on one side, and the swamp of old, often bloated because of compatibility with the most obscure systems, and heterogeneous junk on the other.</p>
<p>It would be nice to point out some articles that show systemd in a good light for a contrast, but currently the <a href="https://duckduckgo.com/?q=systemd+good&amp;ia=web">“systemd good” search query</a> yields results such as “<a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/2841873/meet-systemd-the-controversial-project-taking-over-a-linux-distro-near-you.html">Meet systemd, the controversial project taking over a Linux distro near you</a>”, “<a href="http://www.infoworld.com/article/2608798/data-center/systemd--harbinger-of-the-linux-apocalypse.html">Systemd: Harbinger of the Linux apocalypse</a>”, “<a href="http://linuxbsdos.com/2014/09/03/is-systemd-as-bad-as-boycott-systemd-is-trying-to-make-it/">Is systemd as bad as boycott systemd is trying to make it?</a>”, followed by Wikipedia, suckless, ArchWiki, some tutorials, and <a href="https://judecnelson.blogspot.com/2014/09/systemd-biggest-fallacies.html#!">more</a> <a href="https://www.textplain.net/blog/2015/problems-with-systemd-and-why-i-like-bsd-init/">criticizm</a>.</p>
<p>Well, at least it reached its alleged goal of being more like MS Windows: very few people seem to like it, yet it is used widely.</p>
<p>One of the lessons to learn from this is the following: fix your stuff in time, or Lennart will do it, and nobody will be happy.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>StartSSL and friends</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/startssl-and-friends.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/startssl-and-friends.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/startcom-logo.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">StartCom, Qihoo 360, WoSign, and Opera</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        October  2, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <h2 id="startssl-and-startcom">StartSSL and StartCom</h2>
<p>As you probably already know, and as it has already been mentioned in the “<a href="letsencrypt-public-beta.html">Let’s Encrypt: public beta</a>” article, <a href="https://www.startssl.com/">StartSSL</a> is a crappy (though not outstanding in that) certificate authority. The company behind it is Israel-based <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/StartCom">StartCom</a>, and as the Wikipedia article points out, its root certificates have been shipped with all major browsers since 2010, though the startssl.com domain name was created on 2006-09-10.</p>
<p>Apparently “StartCom” stands for “start commerce”, and their slogan is “StartCom, the Start of eCommerce”. When they’ve just launched StartSSL (assuming it was after 2006-09-10), TLS 1.1 was already out, but “SSL” was a more widely known term among clueless potential customers. That was a subtle hint of what to expect. Since then it only went downhill.</p>
<p>In 2011, shortly after <a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/03/23/gmail_microsoft_web_credential_forgeries/">Comodo</a>, it <a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/06/21/startssl_security_breach/">suffered a security breach</a>, but apparently nothing of value has been stolen, so it wasn’t such big of a deal. It wasn’t considered a biggie even with Comodo, though it has potentially screwed a lot of users.</p>
<p>In 2016, StartCom launched StartEncrypt – a Let’s Encrypt clone, but <a href="https://www.computest.nl/blog/startencrypt-considered-harmful-today/">vulnerable</a>, issuing certificates without confirmation.</p>
<h2 id="opera">Opera</h2>
<p>Opera was a proprietary web browser, perhaps not particularly bad one, which began in 1994, and grew into a monster and pretty much died about 2013. The developers refused to open its source code even after that, managing to sell the poor thing to some Chinese corporation for a hefty bulk of money like a large shipment of old electronics.</p>
<h2 id="wosign-and-qihoo-360">WoSign and Qihoo 360</h2>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qihoo">Qihoo 360</a> is <a href="https://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/qihoo-360-secure-the-most-popular-browser-youve-never-heard-of--cms-24074">a huge Chinese scam</a> that brands its malware as security products, which is, alas, not that uncommon – there indeed seems to be a large overlap between commercial security (or commercial anything, perhaps) and outright fraud. As StartCom, they are not really trying to mimic a decent company: as the linked article mentions, their “<a href="http://se.360.cn/">security browser</a>” logo is just that of IE, but green.</p>
<p>Assuming that people wouldn’t tell lies on the internet (<a href="https://twitter.com/vtlynch/status/777882757548634113">1</a> and <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=12617659">2</a> by the same author, <a href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/startssl-byl-potichu-koupen-wosign-a-prestehovan-do-ciny/">3</a>), and inferring it from the verifiable fact that WoSign is hosted by “QiHU 360 Inc.”, it seems that Qihoo owns WoSign, though Qihoo is not mentioned on the “<a href="https://www.wosign.com/english/about.htm">About WoSign</a>” page (warning: poor English).</p>
<p>The Mozilla wiki “<a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/CA:WoSign_Issues">CA:WoSign Issues</a>” page currently outlines 14 pretty serious issues, occasionally linking bugzilla threads such as <a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1293366#c3">#1293366</a>.</p>
<h2 id="a-pile-formed">A pile formed</h2>
<p>Recently <a href="https://www.wosign.com/english/News/WoSign_completed_equity_investment_to_StartCom_CA.htm">WoSign invested into StartCom</a>, and now hosts its servers. Meantime, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016/07/18/opera-browser-sold-to-a-chinese-consortium-for-600-million/">Qihoo purchased Opera browser</a>, forming a larger pile consisting mostly of scam, and of one corpse.</p>
<h2 id="mozilla-apple-microsoft-and-the-other-one">Mozilla, Apple, Microsoft, and the other one</h2>
<p>One may think that operating system and web browser maintainers shouldn’t have included that crap into distributions at all, but it wasn’t that much worse than the alternatives at the time. One may also think that shipping X.509 certificates is not something a web browser should do in the first place, but it’s not the only thing they do in addition to rendering HTML.</p>
<p>But now <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/mozilla-to-chinas-wosign-well-kill-firefox-trust-in-you-after-mis-issued-github-certs/">Mozilla proposed to get rid of that</a>, <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?_escaped_fragment_=topic/mozilla.dev.security.policy/lWJ1zdUJPLI#!topic/mozilla.dev.security.policy/lWJ1zdUJPLI">Apple does some half-assed job at that</a>, while the other two major browser developers, Microsoft and Google/Alphabet/whatever, don’t seem to react. It’s going pretty slowly, and one of the explanations is that users would do really stupid things (such as disabling validation completely) if they won’t be able to access some websites because of CA blacklisting.</p>
<h2 id="lessons-learned">Lessons learned</h2>
<p>None.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Friendship as a service</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/life/friendship-as-a-service.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/life/friendship-as-a-service.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info life">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/friendship-as-a-service.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Friends from a cloud</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Jacopo_Pontormo_-_Portrait_of_Two_Friends_-_WGA18109.jpg">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        public domain
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 23, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/life.html">life</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>The latest <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing">cloud technology</a> advancement is here, and it is called “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friendship">friendship</a> as a service” (FaaS). Some critics claim that it is pretty similar to the good old GaaS (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Girlfriend_experience">girlfriend as a service</a>), and not really an innovation, but MaaS (marketing as a service) provides some compelling evidence of it being indeed new by pointing to the almighty cloud, and promising that now you can get as much friendship as you want, when and where you want, for a reasonable price.</p>
<p>Other critics claim that it is just <a href="http://www.thefreedictionary.com/escort">escort</a>, but as we shall see, FaaS goes beyond traditional escort services.</p>
<p>As it often happens with technologies, the idea was first contemplated in fiction, such as one of the “<a href="/articles/video/pushing-daisies.html">Pushing Daisies</a>” episodes, where the service was called “<a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1127264/">frescort</a>”, which is short for “friend escort”. But now we have actual commercial services, one of which is <a href="http://rentafriend.com/">RentAFriend.com</a>.</p>
<p>As RentAFriend points out, “there are over 621,585 Friends available for rent worldwide”, and the available activities include pretty much all the conventional friend activities.</p>
<p>What distinguishes FaaS from all the other rental-related things rebranded into “something-as-a-service” and themed with clouds, is that friendship wasn’t explicitly rental-related before, or at least that was rare enough to stay unheard of: if one didn’t have enough imagination to get imaginary friends, they had to hang out with mostly random people, occasionally finding those who they can communicate with, so that they can do stuff together. But it was hard and time-consuming, while not even always leading to the desired results. So people were using other kinds of services that provide human interaction instead, but not quite getting what they wanted to. The solution looks fairly obvious if you think of it now, but nobody has implemented it before: with FaaS, you just pay somebody per hour to pretend being your friend.</p>
<p>The rented friends can pretend being interested in any freaky shit you are into, or simply help you to not feel awkward for or bored because of staying alone while visiting a social event. You also get to choose friends instead of getting more or less random ones, and the relationships are conveniently limited to transactions.</p>
<p>“Friends will NEVER see your name, email address, or any of your personal information”, as RentAFriend <a href="https://rentafriend.com/join/">claims</a>: no sneaky friend will violate your privacy anymore. Its creators seem to indeed care about privacy, not identifying themselves on the website or in its whois records. Though it’s probably bullshit anyway, since they also claim that “you will never receive any mail or phone calls from us. We respect your privacy concerns and assure your information will never be shared or sold to anyone”, while <a href="http://rentafriend.com/privacy/">their T&amp;Cs</a> state that “[y]ou may also receive emails from 3rd party advertisers to the email provided in your account and your agreement during registration”, and do mention that some of the data about you may be sold.</p>
<p>Anyways, one shady service doesn’t compromise the whole idea, and it is always possible to find frescorts without such a service: some of them work on streets, hanging around without any apparent purpose. One can approach them, settle on the price, and go be friends for a few hours. Just keep in mind that undercover cops may hang there as well, so you shouldn’t explicitly mention “friendship for money”, unless it is legal in the state or country you are in.</p>
<hr />
<p>Advertisement: <a href="/">Friendly nurses befriend a terminally ill guy [HD Video]</a>.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Video Game High School</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/video/vghs.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/video/vghs.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info video">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/vghs.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Fun web series</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2170584/">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 22, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/video.html">video</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        web series
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Video_Game_High_School">VGHS</a> pictures a place where people just play computer games all day long, and they call it a school. It may look fun, but <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ESports">professional gaming</a> is a thing, and as professional sports in general, it sucks all the joy from games, turning those into income sources and stressful jobs for gamers, weird amusement and gambling opportunity for the masses, and marketing opportunity for companies. But the show does not bring up the sad bits of professional gaming, keeping it rather lighthearted.</p>
<p>The next thing that you notice is exaggregation of pretty much everything – as in caricatures, or in those asian cartoons. There’s almost no realistic characters, but that makes the show rather fun. It’s also quite interesting how that works out: sometimes the characters act so cute, pretentious, or silly that it may make you to smile and laugh.</p>
<p>The main character (portrayed by the actor known for such roles as Bartender, Tea Guest, Boy on Bike, Guy, and Douche) is rather annoying: he is a disgusting kind of nerd, dully reacting to the things that happen around, which is probably supposed to be relatable. Plenty of nice things happen to him from the very beginning, which is the plot of every asian cartoon, as I’ve heard. To elaborate on the “disgusting” part: it’s the kind of disgusting where you suspect that the actor has a few different health issues, and that it wouldn’t be nice to criticize him for that. It’s good that I don’t care.</p>
<p>Following the annoying tradition of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tron">TRON</a>, during the games, the characters are placed in a game world, but somehow it’s not that bad, even though doesn’t always make sense. The plot twists are predictable sometimes, but then again – the show isn’t supposed to be taken seriously, so that’s fine.</p>
<p>The season structure makes it closer to regular shows: the first season is okay, the second one is probably the most fun, and the third one deals with boring character relationships. Fortunately, it ended before getting even worse; actually it’d be disappointing if it ended when it was good, so ending after a decay is a rather nice way out.</p>
<p>The show is available for free on <code>youtube-dl https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLsMtUWKCmBPRFzqglpk4YQlNFy8wzSXBN</code>.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Oolite</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/games/oolite.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/games/oolite.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info games">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/oolite.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Space and lasers. Lasers in space.</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 22, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://oolite.org/">http://oolite.org/</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/games.html">games</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        space
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oolite_%28video_game%29">Oolite</a> is a rather trashy game, pretty much just <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elite_%28video_game%29">Elite</a> with poor graphics. It’s not just that it is not polished or the gameplay is boring, but it’s screwed by really weird choices – such as barely readable black-on-red and red-on-black captions, and extremely annoying and hard-to-get-rid-of pets.</p>
<p>But. It is set in space, and there are lasers, what almost makes up for the trashy bits. There is trading, long and boring flights, long and boring battles, and some other activities – such as parcel delivery and occasional quests. A few ship upgrades, a bit more if you use extension packs – though it’s somewhat weird and feels like borderline cheating to add items.</p>
<p>It could be called an arcade game, since there’s the same shit over and over again, without any goal. Probably it was cool in 1984, when Elite was first published, but it was 32 years ago – it can be considered vintage now.</p>
<p>Yet, it is playable, and even enjoyable – even if it’s just because of the space and lasers.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Smooth criminal</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/life/smooth-criminal.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/life/smooth-criminal.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info life">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/smoothie.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">The liquid danger</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Blueberry_smoothie.jpg">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en">CC BY-SA 3.0</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 20, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/life.html">life</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>While the magazines that have any audience are suspected in being paid by smoothie corporations to stay silent, The Asocial conducts an investigation on the topic, following the rumors of smoothies being a major risk factor in becoming a hipster.</p>
<h2 id="a-creep">A creep</h2>
<p>We interview a creep, who has got leg <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Necrosis">necrosis</a> as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slim_fit_pants">shrinked pants syndrome</a> complication. That’s what news media usually does in order to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Appeal_to_pity">appeal to pity</a>, and to get a convincing story by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cherry_picking_%28fallacy%29">cherry picking</a> and/or using a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biased_sample">biased sample</a>, so we’ve figured we’ll do the same – and maybe will get paid by the smoothie corporations one day.</p>
<p>The creep’s legs look disgusting, and he does not like being photographed in this condition, so we will not put a picture here.</p>
<p><strong>The Asocial (A)</strong>: So, how are you doing?</p>
<p><strong>Creep (C)</strong>: How does it look I’m doing?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Fine?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Not quite, I have leg necrosis.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Don’t be a whimp, nobody is completely healthy.</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: There are fucking maggots in my legs.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Calm down, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_parasite">human parasites</a> are not that uncommon.</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Did I mention dead flesh?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Fuck it, we’ll find another creep.</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Hey, wait, I’ll give the interview.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Okay. So, you’ve got the necrosis because of the slim pants you were wearing, right?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Yup.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: And you were wearing the slim pants because you were a hipster, is that correct?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Yes, and I still am.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: But no slim pants anymore, huh?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: I have to wear therapeutic pants now.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Did you become a hipster because of the smoothies you were consuming?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: That’s what the doctors say.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: But what do you think?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Well, I guess that it contributed, at least.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Okay. Any word of advice to our readers?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Smoothies are the shit.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Do you mean that they are good?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Yeah, but you’d better not even try them.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: You’re not making much sense now.</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Want to see my leg?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Put that away, please.</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Want to touch it?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: That’s enough for the interview, I hope you’ll die soon.</p>
<h2 id="dr.fraud">Dr. Fraud</h2>
<p>Dr. Fraud is a man in doctor clothing (trustworthiness +4), glasses (intelligence +3), and with a stethoscope (charisma +3). He looks like he knows everything about medicine and follows all the recent research, so we’re interviewing him as well.</p>
<p><strong>The Asocial (A)</strong>: Is it true that each smoothie shrinks your pants’ leg opening diameter by 0.5 mm?</p>
<p><strong>Dr. Fraud (F)</strong>: What? Where did you get that from?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Made it up just now, actually.</p>
<p><strong>F</strong>: Oh. Well, let’s see. Here is the data we have – that’s how many people turn after their <em>n</em>th smoothie:</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="/images/articles/smooth-criminal-plot-1.svg" alt="people turned into hipsters after consuming their nth smoothie" />
<p class="caption">people turned into hipsters after consuming their nth smoothie</p>
</div>
<!-- s = 0:10:490 -->
<!-- h = [3,2,0,0,0,0,1,0,0,0,0,0,4,8,7,1,5,11,20,4,6,1,1,3,4,3,5,7,9,13,14,11,8,12,8,8,7,3,1,1,1,2,1,2,1,0,0,0,0,0] -->
<p>Or, to visualize it a bit differently – that’s how many people are hipsters after consuming <em>n</em> smoothies:</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="/images/articles/smooth-criminal-plot-2.svg" alt="people turned into hipsters after consuming n smoothies" />
<p class="caption">people turned into hipsters after consuming n smoothies</p>
</div>
<!-- h2 = [3,5,5,5,5,5,6,6,6,6,6,6,10,18,25,26,31,42,62,66,72,73,74,77,81,84,89,96,105,118,132,143,151,163,171,179,186,189,190,191,192,194,195,197,198,198,198,198,198,198] -->
<p>That’s from a study with 100000 smoothies and 200 subjects, 198 of which turned into hipsters by the end of the experiment, and the remaining two were probably immune. Hm, wait, that’s less than 0.05 of the sample, so it could be seen as insignificant – in fact, we could claim that they turn after 390 smoothies. Round it up to 400, and it’d be 0.25 mm per smoothie, if a leg opening shrinks by 10 cm on average once one turns into a hipster. But that’s only what’s expected after 400 smoothies, while it would be different for pretty much any other amount.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Interesting. But it assumes that the pants only shrink once, when one becomes a hipster, right?</p>
<p><strong>F</strong>: Yeah, we can’t tell much about further shrinking from this study, and that 10 cm value should be checked as well. But the order of magnitude should be about right.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: What about the timing? Is the effect the same when one drinks 390 smoothies in, say, a month, and when one does that in a year?</p>
<p><strong>F</strong>: No idea. It’s just written here that in the study, 2 smoothies per day were used. Maybe it’s an average or something.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Is it the same for different smoothies, and does the volume of a smoothie matter?</p>
<p><strong>F</strong>: Listen, I’m not really a doctor.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Well, I’m not really a journalist.</p>
<p><strong>F</strong>: Want to grab a smoothie, then?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Sure.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Emacs 25 and Vim 8 released</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/emacs-25-and-vim-8-released.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/emacs-25-and-vim-8-released.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info computing">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/emacs-and-vim.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">On the same week</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 19, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/computing.html">computing</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>After years of development, there are new major releases of both <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/">Emacs</a> and <a href="https://www.vim.org/">Vim</a>: “<a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?_escaped_fragment_=topic/vim_announce/EKTuhjF3ET0#!topic/vim_announce/EKTuhjF3ET0">Vim 8.0 released!</a>”, “<a href="https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/info-gnu-emacs/2016-09/msg00000.html">Emacs 25.1 released</a>”. Emacs is somewhat unusual in versioning, so don’t get confused: 25.1 is the first stable release, while 25.0 was for unstable ones.</p>
<p>Highlights of the highlights listed in the release notes: Emacs now has C FFI and Xwidgets support, while Vim got asynchronous I/O and closures.</p>
<p>Both emacs and vi were initially released in 1976, and both are trying to provide efficient controls and extensibility. Both seem to be extremely slow in adopting new features<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a> in their extension languages, and neither can just switch to a sane language, since that would break tons of code and configuration files written in the past decades. As even the last changes suggest, Emacs is not called an “operating system” for nothing, while Vim still tries to be just a text editor.</p>
<p>Things go as usual, and perhaps the biggest surprise here is that Vim finally got ahead of Emacs in something: in stable major release date, by a few days.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Well, FFIs, asynchronous I/O, and closures were there even before 1976, so it can be generalized to any features.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
