<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>The Asocial</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://theasocial.com" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>The Asocial</name>
        <email>info@theasocial.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2016-09-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Friendship as a service</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/life/friendship-as-a-service.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/life/friendship-as-a-service.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info life">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/friendship-as-a-service.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Friends from a cloud</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Jacopo_Pontormo_-_Portrait_of_Two_Friends_-_WGA18109.jpg">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        public domain
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 23, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/life.html">life</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>The latest <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing">cloud technology</a> advancement is here, and it is called “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friendship">friendship</a> as a service” (FaaS). Some critics claim that it is pretty similar to the good old GaaS (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Girlfriend_experience">girlfriend as a service</a>), and not really an innovation, but MaaS (marketing as a service) provides some compelling evidence of it being indeed new by pointing to the almighty cloud, and promising that now you can get as much friendship as you want, when and where you want, for a reasonable price.</p>
<p>Other critics claim that it is just <a href="http://www.thefreedictionary.com/escort">escort</a>, but as we shall see, FaaS goes beyond traditional escort services.</p>
<p>As it often happens with technologies, the idea was first contemplated in fiction, such as one of the “<a href="/articles/video/pushing-daisies.html">Pushing Daisies</a>” episodes, where the service was called “<a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1127264/">frescort</a>”, which is short for “friend escort”. But now we have actual commercial services, one of which is <a href="http://rentafriend.com/">RentAFriend.com</a>.</p>
<p>As RentAFriend points out, “there are over 621,585 Friends available for rent worldwide”, and the available activities include pretty much all the conventional friend activities.</p>
<p>What distinguishes FaaS from all the other rental-related things rebranded into “something-as-a-service” and themed with clouds, is that friendship wasn’t explicitly rental-related before, or at least that was rare enough to stay unheard of: if one didn’t have enough imagination to get imaginary friends, they had to hang out with mostly random people, occasionally finding those who they can communicate with, so that they can do stuff together. But it was hard and time-consuming, while not even always leading to the desired results. So people were using other kinds of services that provide human interaction instead, but not quite getting what they wanted to. The solution looks fairly obvious if you think of it now, but nobody has implemented it before: with FaaS, you just pay somebody per hour to pretend being your friend.</p>
<p>The rented friends can pretend being interested in any freaky shit you are into, or simply help you to not feel awkward for or bored because of staying alone while visiting a social event. You also get to choose friends instead of getting more or less random ones, and the relationships are conveniently limited to transactions.</p>
<p>“Friends will NEVER see your name, email address, or any of your personal information”, as RentAFriend <a href="https://rentafriend.com/join/">claims</a>: no sneaky friend will violate your privacy anymore. Its creators seem to indeed care about privacy, not identifying themselves on the website or in its whois records. Though it’s probably bullshit anyway, since they also claim that “you will never receive any mail or phone calls from us. We respect your privacy concerns and assure your information will never be shared or sold to anyone”, while <a href="http://rentafriend.com/privacy/">their T&amp;Cs</a> state that “[y]ou may also receive emails from 3rd party advertisers to the email provided in your account and your agreement during registration”, and do mention that some of the data about you may be sold.</p>
<p>Anyways, one shady service doesn’t compromise the whole idea, and it is always possible to find frescorts without such a service: some of them work on streets, hanging around without any apparent purpose. One can approach them, settle on the price, and go be friends for a few hours. Just keep in mind that undercover cops may hang there as well, so you shouldn’t explicitly mention “friendship for money”, unless it is legal in the state or country you are in.</p>
<hr />
<p>Advertisement: <a href="/">Friendly nurses befriend a terminally ill guy [HD Video]</a>.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Video Game High School</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/video/vghs.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/video/vghs.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info video">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/vghs.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Fun web series</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2170584/">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 22, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/video.html">video</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        web series
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Video_Game_High_School">VGHS</a> pictures a place where people just play computer games all day long, and they call it a school. It may look fun, but <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ESports">professional gaming</a> is a thing, and as professional sports in general, it sucks all the joy from games, turning those into income sources and stressful jobs for gamers, weird amusement and gambling opportunity for the masses, and marketing opportunity for companies. But the show does not bring up the sad bits of professional gaming, keeping it rather lighthearted.</p>
<p>The next thing that you notice is exaggregation of pretty much everything – as in caricatures, or in those asian cartoons. There’s almost no realistic characters, but that makes the show rather fun. It’s also quite interesting how that works out: sometimes the characters act so cute, pretentious, or silly that it may make you to smile and laugh.</p>
<p>The main character (portrayed by the actor known for such roles as Bartender, Tea Guest, Boy on Bike, Guy, and Douche) is rather annoying: he is a disgusting kind of nerd, dully reacting to the things that happen around, which is probably supposed to be relatable. Plenty of nice things happen to him from the very beginning, which is the plot of every asian cartoon, as I’ve heard. To elaborate on the “disgusting” part: it’s the kind of disgusting where you suspect that the actor has a few different health issues, and that it wouldn’t be nice to criticize him for that. It’s good that I don’t care.</p>
<p>Following the annoying tradition of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tron">TRON</a>, during the games, the characters are placed in a game world, but somehow it’s not that bad, even though doesn’t always make sense. The plot twists are predictable sometimes, but then again – the show isn’t supposed to be taken seriously, so that’s fine.</p>
<p>The season structure makes it closer to regular shows: the first season is okay, the second one is probably the most fun, and the third one deals with boring character relationships. Fortunately, it ended before getting even worse; actually it’d be disappointing if it ended when it was good, so ending after a decay is a rather nice way out.</p>
<p>The show is available for free on <code>youtube-dl https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLsMtUWKCmBPRFzqglpk4YQlNFy8wzSXBN</code>.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Oolite</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/games/oolite.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/games/oolite.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info games">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/oolite.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Space and lasers. Lasers in space.</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 22, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://oolite.org/">http://oolite.org/</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/games.html">games</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        space
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oolite_%28video_game%29">Oolite</a> is a rather trashy game, pretty much just <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elite_%28video_game%29">Elite</a> with poor graphics. It’s not just that it is not polished or the gameplay is boring, but it’s screwed by really weird choices – such as barely readable black-on-red and red-on-black captions, and extremely annoying and hard-to-get-rid-of pets.</p>
<p>But. It is set in space, and there are lasers, what almost makes up for the trashy bits. There is trading, long and boring flights, long and boring battles, and some other activities – such as parcel delivery and occasional quests. A few ship upgrades, a bit more if you use extension packs – though it’s somewhat weird and feels like borderline cheating to add items.</p>
<p>It could be called an arcade game, since there’s the same shit over and over again, without any goal. Probably it was cool in 1984, when Elite was first published, but it was 32 years ago – it can be considered vintage now.</p>
<p>Yet, it is playable, and even enjoyable – even if it’s just because of the space and lasers.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Smooth criminal</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/life/smooth-criminal.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/life/smooth-criminal.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info life">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/smoothie.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">The liquid danger</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Blueberry_smoothie.jpg">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en">CC BY-SA 3.0</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 20, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/life.html">life</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>While the magazines that have any audience are suspected in being paid by smoothie corporations to stay silent, The Asocial conducts an investigation on the topic, following the rumors of smoothies being a major risk factor in becoming a hipster.</p>
<h2 id="a-creep">A creep</h2>
<p>We interview a creep, who has got leg <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Necrosis">necrosis</a> as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slim_fit_pants">shrinked pants syndrome</a> complication. That’s what news media usually does in order to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Appeal_to_pity">appeal to pity</a>, and to get a convincing story by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cherry_picking_%28fallacy%29">cherry picking</a> and/or using a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biased_sample">biased sample</a>, so we’ve figured we’ll do the same – and maybe will get paid by the smoothie corporations one day.</p>
<p>The creep’s legs look disgusting, and he does not like being photographed in this condition, so we will not put a picture here.</p>
<p><strong>The Asocial (A)</strong>: So, how are you doing?</p>
<p><strong>Creep (C)</strong>: How does it look I’m doing?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Fine?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Not quite, I have leg necrosis.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Don’t be a whimp, nobody is completely healthy.</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: There are fucking maggots in my legs.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Calm down, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_parasite">human parasites</a> are not that uncommon.</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Did I mention dead flesh?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Fuck it, we’ll find another creep.</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Hey, wait, I’ll give the interview.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Okay. So, you’ve got the necrosis because of the slim pants you were wearing, right?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Yup.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: And you were wearing the slim pants because you were a hipster, is that correct?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Yes, and I still am.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: But no slim pants anymore, huh?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: I have to wear therapeutic pants now.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Did you become a hipster because of the smoothies you were consuming?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: That’s what the doctors say.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: But what do you think?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Well, I guess that it contributed, at least.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Okay. Any word of advice to our readers?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Smoothies are the shit.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Do you mean that they are good?</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Yeah, but you’d better not even try them.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: You’re not making much sense now.</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Want to see my leg?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Put that away, please.</p>
<p><strong>C</strong>: Want to touch it?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: That’s enough for the interview, I hope you’ll die soon.</p>
<h2 id="dr.fraud">Dr. Fraud</h2>
<p>Dr. Fraud is a man in doctor clothing (trustworthiness +4), glasses (intelligence +3), and with a stethoscope (charisma +3). He looks like he knows everything about medicine and follows all the recent research, so we’re interviewing him as well.</p>
<p><strong>The Asocial (A)</strong>: Is it true that each smoothie shrinks your pants’ leg opening diameter by 0.5 mm?</p>
<p><strong>Dr. Fraud (F)</strong>: What? Where did you get that from?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Made it up just now, actually.</p>
<p><strong>F</strong>: Oh. Well, let’s see. Here is the data we have – that’s how many people turn after their <em>n</em>th smoothie:</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="/images/articles/smooth-criminal-plot-1.svg" alt="people turned into hipsters after consuming their nth smoothie" />
<p class="caption">people turned into hipsters after consuming their nth smoothie</p>
</div>
<!-- s = 0:10:490 -->
<!-- h = [3,2,0,0,0,0,1,0,0,0,0,0,4,8,7,1,5,11,20,4,6,1,1,3,4,3,5,7,9,13,14,11,8,12,8,8,7,3,1,1,1,2,1,2,1,0,0,0,0,0] -->
<p>Or, to visualize it a bit differently – that’s how many people are hipsters after consuming <em>n</em> smoothies:</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="/images/articles/smooth-criminal-plot-2.svg" alt="people turned into hipsters after consuming n smoothies" />
<p class="caption">people turned into hipsters after consuming n smoothies</p>
</div>
<!-- h2 = [3,5,5,5,5,5,6,6,6,6,6,6,10,18,25,26,31,42,62,66,72,73,74,77,81,84,89,96,105,118,132,143,151,163,171,179,186,189,190,191,192,194,195,197,198,198,198,198,198,198] -->
<p>That’s from a study with 100000 smoothies and 200 subjects, 198 of which turned into hipsters by the end of the experiment, and the remaining two were probably immune. Hm, wait, that’s less than 0.05 of the sample, so it could be seen as insignificant – in fact, we could claim that they turn after 390 smoothies. Round it up to 400, and it’d be 0.25 mm per smoothie, if a leg opening shrinks by 10 cm on average once one turns into a hipster. But that’s only what’s expected after 400 smoothies, while it would be different for pretty much any other amount.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Interesting. But it assumes that the pants only shrink once, when one becomes a hipster, right?</p>
<p><strong>F</strong>: Yeah, we can’t tell much about further shrinking from this study, and that 10 cm value should be checked as well. But the order of magnitude should be about right.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: What about the timing? Is the effect the same when one drinks 390 smoothies in, say, a month, and when one does that in a year?</p>
<p><strong>F</strong>: No idea. It’s just written here that in the study, 2 smoothies per day were used. Maybe it’s an average or something.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Is it the same for different smoothies, and does the volume of a smoothie matter?</p>
<p><strong>F</strong>: Listen, I’m not really a doctor.</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Well, I’m not really a journalist.</p>
<p><strong>F</strong>: Want to grab a smoothie, then?</p>
<p><strong>A</strong>: Sure.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Emacs 25 and Vim 8 released</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/emacs-25-and-vim-8-released.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/emacs-25-and-vim-8-released.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info computing">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/emacs-and-vim.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">On the same week</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 19, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/computing.html">computing</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>After years of development, there are new major releases of both <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/">Emacs</a> and <a href="https://www.vim.org/">Vim</a>: “<a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?_escaped_fragment_=topic/vim_announce/EKTuhjF3ET0#!topic/vim_announce/EKTuhjF3ET0">Vim 8.0 released!</a>”, “<a href="https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/info-gnu-emacs/2016-09/msg00000.html">Emacs 25.1 released</a>”. Emacs is somewhat unusual in versioning, so don’t get confused: 25.1 is the first stable release, while 25.0 was for unstable ones.</p>
<p>Highlights of the highlights listed in the release notes: Emacs now has C FFI and Xwidgets support, while Vim got asynchronous I/O and closures.</p>
<p>Both emacs and vi were initially released in 1976, and both are trying to provide efficient controls and extensibility. Both seem to be extremely slow in adopting new features<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a> in their extension languages, and neither can just switch to a sane language, since that would break tons of code and configuration files written in the past decades. As even the last changes suggest, Emacs is not called an “operating system” for nothing, while Vim still tries to be just a text editor.</p>
<p>Things go as usual, and perhaps the biggest surprise here is that Vim finally got ahead of Emacs in something: in stable major release date, by a few days.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Well, FFIs, asynchronous I/O, and closures were there even before 1976, so it can be generalized to any features.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Search keywords</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/search-keywords.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/search-keywords.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-15T06:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-15T06:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info comics">
  
  <img src="/images/comics/search-keywords.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Whoa, we are popular</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 15, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/comics.html">comics</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Mr. Robot</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/video/mr-robot.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/video/mr-robot.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info video">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/mr-robot.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Identifying bad bits in a good show</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://www.usanetwork.com/mrrobot">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 15, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/video.html">video</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        tv series
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mr._Robot_%28TV_series%29">Mr. Robot</a> is a rather good show about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_hacker">security hacking</a> and other loosely related things, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_anxiety_disorder">SAD</a>.</p>
<p>The prominent feature of this show is its connection to reality: there is actual software instead of 3-dimensional interfaces, and the protagonist is at least somewhat <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geek">geeky</a>. Though it is not really new, for there were series such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Scene_%28miniseries%29">The Scene</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_IT_Crowd">The IT Crowd</a>, and perhaps <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lone_Gunmen_%28TV_series%29">The Lone Gunmen</a>, Mr. Robot might be the first show to combine geeky characters with real software. Well, except for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Big_Bang_Theory">The Big Bang Theory</a>. But maybe it’s still the first to do it to such extent.</p>
<p>The plot itself is quite decent, though the first major plot twist appears to be borrowed from another movie, which is rather strange. The show itself tells a continued story – not just the same plot with variables filled with different values from episode to episode. However, once you get used to reality in a show, you may begin to expect accuracy and plausibility, but that’s where the show gets worse. There are clichés, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leet">leetspeak</a> in both writing and speech, to begin with. Then there is software: the protagonist is supposed to be experienced and geeky, so one would expect him to be using both efficient and advanced tools. But what we observe is mouse-driven <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNOME">GNOME</a>, sometimes with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNU_nano">nano</a><a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a><a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2"><sup>2</sup></a><a href="#fn3" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref3"><sup>3</sup></a><a href="#fn4" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref4"><sup>4</sup></a><a href="#fn5" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref5"><sup>5</sup></a><a href="#fn6" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref6"><sup>6</sup></a><a href="#fn7" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref7"><sup>7</sup></a> in a terminal emulator. Though it may be argued that GNOME is being featured there because of it being the default desktop environment for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kali_Linux">Kali</a> GNU/Linux distribution, or because it allows one to just focus on the job without dealing with WM and system configuration manually, nano on top of that makes little sense: there is basically <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Editor_war">two advanced text editors</a>, and nano is not one of them. Even for a newbie user, it would not make much sense to use GNOME, and then nano in a terminal emulator: there is gedit for such users. To be fair, it seems that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vi">vi</a> is also used sometimes, but sometimes there’s also <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ubuntu_%28operating_system%29">Ubuntu</a>. Although, it may be a matter of taste, and something overly geeky would probably also look like a cliché.</p>
<p>In S02E06, they are preparing a newbie to attack FBI. Here is a hilarious screen:</p>
<pre><code>root@OpenWrt:~/exploit_dev/bin# ./EnableAttack femtoponWLAN
Usage: ./EnableAttack &lt;attack name&gt; &lt;interfaces&gt; &lt;timing&gt;
root@OpenWrt:~/exploit_dev/bin# ./EnableAttack femtopwn WLANWLAN22
Usage: ./EnableAttack &lt;attack name&gt; &lt;interfaces&gt; &lt;timing&gt;
root@OpenWrt:~/exploit_dev/bin#</code></pre>
<p>Then the guy who is teaching the newbie suggests to visualize the attack, showing pictures of the devices. And dictates the command: “period, forward slash, enable attack, space, femtopwn, space, WLAN0, comma, WLAN1, space, two”. The screen again:</p>
<pre><code>root@OpenWrt:~/exploit_dev/bin# ./EnableAttack femtoponWLAN
Usage: ./EnableAttack &lt;attack name&gt; &lt;interfaces&gt; &lt;timing&gt;
root@OpenWrt:~/exploit_dev/bin# ./EnableAttack femtopwn WLANWLAN22
Usage: ./EnableAttack &lt;attack name&gt; &lt;interfaces&gt; &lt;timing&gt;
root@OpenWrt:~/exploit_dev/bin# ./EnableAttack femtopwn WLAN1WLAN22
Usage: ./EnableAttack &lt;attack name&gt; &lt;interfaces&gt; &lt;timing&gt;
root@OpenWrt:~/exploit_dev/bin#</code></pre>
<p>Though it is funny, and mental disability of the hacker-to-be may be assumed without hurting the plot, it is rather hard to imagine why wouldn’t they just set a shell script instead of making the poor kid who can neither write what’s dictated nor read the instructions to memorize the commands, without any understanding.</p>
<p>“I will get this. Let’s just try it again.” – says the future hacker with a serious face after another failure, apparently implying that she doesn’t get that the problem is that she keeps making typos. In the next scene, the teacher complains: “You can’t teach someone to hack in one day, okay?”, suggesting that “to hack” is “to type without typos”. That for sure takes some time to learn.</p>
<p>A bit later, they use the same rookie as a modem, not just as a shell script. Apparently it all is intended to add visible thrill and human interaction to the process, just as the infamous 3D interfaces are.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the show is rather pleasant to watch.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Nothing’s wrong with nano.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Except for it being useless.<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>Well, I’m using it.<a href="#fnref3">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn4"><p>Is it the reason why you screw formatting all the time?<a href="#fnref4">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn5"><p>Here he goes again. Footnotes are not the place for flamewars, let’s go settle it like men.<a href="#fnref5">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn6"><p>I don’t hit kids.<a href="#fnref6">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn7"><p>That’s it, I’m heading to your table.<a href="#fnref7">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Data breaches</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/data-breaches.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/data-breaches.html</id>
    <published>2016-09-10T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Their extent and consequences</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        September 10, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        security
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <h2 id="first-glance">First glance</h2>
<p>While it is now well-known that companies worldwide are obliged to participate into mass surveillance by sharing your data with state agencies, we are trying to estimate the extent to which regular scam has access to that data.</p>
<p>Perhaps the primary source of data leaks is major <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_breach">data breaches</a>; there’s even a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_data_breaches">list of data breaches</a> in Wikipedia.</p>
<p>Apparently a common belief is that big companies are less likely to exploit your data for much more than <a href="/articles/internet/human-web-trafficking.html">human web trafficking</a>, than, say, Chinese hackers. But sometimes the latter can access the data of the former – including huge techy companies and services, such as Gmail, Ubuntu, Twitter, Facebook, Apple, eBay, Adobe, Everenote, and Dropbox, as well as financial, retail, healthcare, government ones. You hand data to those, they get hacked or accidently publish<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a> it, doing all the collection job for the scam that may be interested.</p>
<h2 id="the-extent">The extent</h2>
<p>The wikipedia list mentions an estimate of 2 billion user entries total, while the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_Internet_usage">amount of internet users</a> is roughly a half of the world population – about 3.5 billion users. With the average <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_literacy_rate">literacy rate</a> of about 85%<a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2"><sup>2</sup></a>, it’s pretty high, and it also suggests why so many websites and programs seem to aim rather inexperienced users. <a href="https://www.leakedsource.com/">LeakedSource</a><a href="#fn3" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref3"><sup>3</sup></a> mentions a similar figure, 2.2 billion accounts in their database. Probably some of the breaches remain untold, but there should be plenty of accounts belonging to the same users, and plenty of spam bots – so the actual number of users whose data was compromised may be, say, an order of magnitude lower than that – hundreds of millions.</p>
<p>That estimate is probably not too high, since some of the individual breaches are reported to contain huge numbers. Here they are, in millions: US Military veterans – 76, TK / TJ Maxx – 94, Target Corporation – 70, 7-Eleven + Nasdaq + others – 160, Heartland – 130, eBay – 145, AOL – 92, Anthem Inc. – 80, Adobe Systems – 152. The LeakedSource website also mentions, among the 20 most recently added databases: Rambler.ru – 98, Last.fm – 43, Dropbox.com – 67.</p>
<h2 id="causes">Causes</h2>
<p>Each breach takes multiple stupid decisions or mistakes: from hiring and assigning those who are not suitable for a job, to actually not doing it properly: computers don’t give data away by themselves, unless they are told to – even if unintentionally.</p>
<p>Though it is in human nature to make mistakes, there are techniques to prevent nearly all of them – such as reviews by competent people, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_proof">formal</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactive_theorem_proving">machine-verified</a> proofs, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Layered_security">layered security</a>, and so on. It is mostly carelessness that leads to the breaches.</p>
<h2 id="data-usage">Data usage</h2>
<p>Many things can happen with the user data which is available to scammers: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phishing">phishing</a> is probably the most basic way to apply it, though one may use that data to get into user accounts on other services, to spam while impersonating them<a href="#fn4" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref4"><sup>4</sup></a>, to resell for future directed attacks, and so on. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientia_potentia_est">Knowledge is power</a>, and it’s rather unjust in this case.</p>
<h2 id="counter-measures">Counter measures</h2>
<p>Entertainment services that require registration can simply be avoided, while others may be rather tricky to avoid. For those, one can just use separate identities: obviously different logins and passwords, no private data such as real name or photos when not necessary, preferably using Tor, etc. A single alternative identity for online activities is not sufficient, since it leads to higher accumulation of data in the hands of scammers than the practically achievable minimum.</p>
<p>Basically, just do the opposite of <a href="/articles/internet/the-kat-founder-got-arrested.html">what Vaulin did</a>.</p>
<h3 id="unauthorized-access-laws">Unauthorized access laws</h3>
<p>As one may guess, those breaches are illegal: that’s unauthorized access to information. Recently Bruce Schneier reposted a couple of related news: “<a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2016/07/visiting_a_webs.html">Visiting a Website against the Owner’s Wishes Is Now a Federal Crime</a>” and “<a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2016/07/password_sharin_1.html">Password Sharing Is Now a Crime</a>”. One of those quotes some guy, who explained “without authorization” as follows:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>An unambiguous, non-technical term that, given its plain and ordinary meaning, means accessing a protected computer without permission.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It’s so unambiguous that we have at least one more unambiguous – though rather technical – <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Authorization">definition in Wikipedia</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Authorization or authorisation is the function of specifying access rights to resources related to information security and computer security in general and to access control in particular. More formally, “to authorize” is to define an access policy.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>At the first glance, they don’t seem to contradict each other: a permission is given (or not) by defining an access policy. Computers are precise, and they follow that policy as programmed. Pretty cool, and it’s pretty much impossible to violate such a policy when it’s implemented using computers.</p>
<p>Alas, people read and understand those unambiguous definitions quite differently. What the guy tried to explain there, is not plain “permission by a strict and unambiguous program”, but “what one <em>really</em> means or wants”. So, when one messes up and fails to define the access policy as they wanted to, and then somebody uses what was in fact defined – it is usually considered an unauthorized access, for which the more competent person is supposed to be punished – since they have probably understood what’s going on. Orin Kerr of The Washington Post <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/volokh-conspiracy/wp/2016/07/12/9th-circuit-its-a-federal-crime-to-visit-a-website-after-being-told-not-to-visit-it/">states</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The main question becomes <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mens_rea">mens rea</a>: The visit becomes a federal crime when the visitor knows that the computer owner doesn’t want it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Indeed, that also explains how the more conventional unauthorized access is deemed illegal. Alas, it’s mostly useless against scam and major data breaches, and may even simplify those by discouraging ethical hackers from penetration testing.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Yes, that’s a thing – pretty common, even.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Ever wondered what it was like to live in the world where most of the human population was savage? Surprise, we’re not far from that.<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>The website itself looks rather scammy, but appears to indeed have those databases.<a href="#fnref3">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn4"><p>Well, that’s what legitimate websites such as LinkedIn are doing already.<a href="#fnref4">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Pushing Daisies</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/video/pushing-daisies.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/video/pushing-daisies.html</id>
    <published>2016-08-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-08-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info video">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/pushing-daisies.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">A fairy tale</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:PushingDaisieslogo2.jpg">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        August 19, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0925266/">http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0925266/</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/video.html">video</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        fantasy
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pushing_Daisies">Pushing Daisies</a> is a cute fairy tale. The characters are quirky and nice, the dialogues are interesting and not realistic, the colors are bright. There’s plenty of other minor and amusing bits, which make the series pretty wonderful when they are put together.</p>
<p>Though there are goofs, at least some of which are pointed out on IMDB, they can be ignored rather easily, since the fantasy bits are explained plainly as “magic”, not “sci-fi”.</p>
<p>The story revolves around the pie maker, who is also a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Necromancy">necromancer</a>. He applies his skills to revive products for pies, and to assist a private investigator in the forensics by reviving dead people and asking who killed them.</p>
<p>It is well worth watching.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The KAT founder got arrested</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/the-kat-founder-got-arrested.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/the-kat-founder-got-arrested.html</id>
    <published>2016-07-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/kat.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">We investigate where things went wrong for him</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Kickasstorrentslogo.png">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        copyright-protected logo
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        July 27, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://kat.am">https://kat.am</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        security
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>As <a href="http://www.wired.co.uk/article/kat-alleged-founder-arrested">Wired</a> and <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2016/07/kickasstorrents-alleged-founder-artem-vaulin-arrested-in-poland/">Ars Technica</a> have reported, Artem Vaulin was recently arrested for being the <a href="https://kat.am/">Kickass Torrents</a> founder. There was lots of noise because KAT was stealing imaginary profit from movie companies, or something like that. In any case, what’s really interesting when such a thing happens, is how exactly he was identified; what was his mistake.</p>
<p>Though Wired and Ars Technica provide some information about his mistakes, it appears to differ, so let’s better read the actual <a href="https://assets.documentcloud.org/documents/2996082/Artem-Vaulin-Complaint.pdf">complaint</a>.</p>
<h2 id="the-investigation">The Investigation</h2>
<p>As one may think, somebody who owns a large torrent tracker should be extremely careful, sometimes even paranoid, since their actions make big companies unhappy. By not preventing users from using their service, they are being an accomplice in the unspeakable crime of file sharing.</p>
<p>Then there should be a fatal slip, where they get identified by a writing style, or by a small piece of information that accidently leaks to a server accessible by a law enforcement agency, or sold by a person they’ve trusted, or timing of their actions allowed to trace the packets to their ISP… well, nothing of that sort has taken place this time.</p>
<p>One day, using KAT, HSI special agents found, downloaded, and watched the following movies: Batman V Superman: Dawn of Justice, Captain America: Civil War, Central Intelligence, Deadpool, Finding Dory, Independence Day: Resurgence, Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Out of the Shadows, X-Men Apocalypse, and Now You See Me 2. Apparently they liked the movies very much, concluded that those should cost at least a million dollars combined. Since Homeland Security had nothing better to do, they’ve opened an investigation.</p>
<p>A special agent, extensively using his or her training and experience, based on which he or she knows great many things, found the following subtle clues:</p>
<ul>
<li>KAT “people” page mentioned at least the owner’s nickname, which was also used for personal mail addresses, when real name wasn’t used (in addresses themselves; was still filled everywhere).</li>
<li>KAT servers didn’t use any disk encryption, easily providing bits of identifying information and helpful evidence.</li>
<li>A fake company was used as a front, with a LinkedIn presence, with real names and photos.</li>
<li>Payments went through regular banks, with records available to the investigator.</li>
<li>Public whois data of a KAT domain registered to Vaulin, with his phone number and address.</li>
<li>Other KAT domains on the same GoDaddy account.</li>
<li>Vaulin’s personal mailboxes on public mail services (Apple’s in particular), with unencrypted KAT-related letters, tons of private information filled, Vaulin’s passport, driver’s license, personal banking information.</li>
<li>A Coinbase account for KAT donations, with real name, address, and that Apple email filled.</li>
<li>Logs of access to the KAT facebook account from the same IP as to the Apple account with the mailbox that contained all the private information, as well as from the same IP that was used to access the Coinbase account.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s when special agent UC-1, by putting it all together, started becoming suspicious of Vaulin: “he might be involved into KAT!”, thought the agent. Further investigation and additional clues added to the suspicion, and Vaulin, despite all his security measures, was finally captured in Poland.</p>
<p>Though it’s not clear how exactly Artem was captured, but judging by his overall secrecy and preparation, one may guess how hard it was: he probably was running naked around a police station and screaming, so the authorities had to besiege the city, as well as to bring a couple of helicopters and a tank, while Poland was targeted by nuclear missiles as a plan B, yet was saved in the last moment, and the villian was finally captured. UC-1 rode a Harley into the sunset, got a promotion, and lived happily ever after.</p>
<h2 id="aftermath">Aftermath</h2>
<p>Wired and Ars Technica call Artem an “alleged founder”, for it’s still to be proved in court. Indeed, perhaps the only way for all this to make sense is if it’ll turn out that Vaulin’s identity has been stolen and used for years by an actual founder, who is not mentally challenged. Yet it is likely that Vaulin will face a big sentence to learn how it feels when your property gets “illegaly shared”, getting an owner of his own instead of being one.</p>
<p>This is a lesson to us all: think twice before stealing priceless masterpieces.</p>
<p>As usual, random officials make <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-ndil/pr/owner-most-visited-illegal-file-sharing-website-charged-criminal-copyright-infringement">bullshit statements</a>.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
