<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>The Asocial</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://theasocial.com" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>The Asocial</name>
        <email>info@theasocial.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2017-05-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>BBS: The Documentary</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/video/bbs-documentary.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/video/bbs-documentary.html</id>
    <published>2017-05-25T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-05-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info video">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/bbs-documentary.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">A documentary about bulletin board systems</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://www.bbsdocumentary.com/">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        May 25, 2017
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://www.bbsdocumentary.com/">http://www.bbsdocumentary.com/</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/video.html">video</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>Remember our journey into the world of <a href="/articles/internet/telnet-bbs.html">telnet BBS</a>? While they are somewhat fun on their own, they only provide glimpses of what it was like to use them when they were popular. But <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BBS:_The_Documentary">BBS: The Documentary</a> provides a more comprehensive overview of various aspects surrounding BBS, focusing on the people who were using and running them.</p>
<p>Through numerous interviews, it covers early BBS communities and stories, the birth of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FidoNet">FidoNet</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MUD">MUD</a> games, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ANSI_art">ANSI art</a> scene, the transformation of some of the BBS into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_service_provider">ISPs</a>, some hardware and software of the time, and other related topics.</p>
<p>While it seems to be rather low-budget, with low audio and video quality, it is genuinely interesting and informative. The film is directed by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jason_Scott_Sadofsky">Jason Scott</a>.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Cloudflare</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/cloudflare.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/cloudflare.html</id>
    <published>2017-05-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-05-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/cloudflare.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">A self-inflicted MitM attack service</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Cloudflare_logo.svg">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        copyrighted logo
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        May 23, 2017
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><em>You may have noticed that we didn’t write much in the past few months. That’s because we’ve been saving our quarterly profanity quota to write about Cloudflare.</em></p>
<p>“Synergy” is a word famous for being abused by useless people, yet it would serve well to describe what combination of Cloudflare with everything connected to it is: a few pieces of shit, the combination of which is a greater piece of shit than the sum of each separately. Or, to put in a more straightforward way, Cloudflare is a shit amplifier.</p>
<p>Consider Google: it milks its users for private information, sells them to spammers (aka advertisers), tries to track others and do the same to them, but fails because JavaScript is disabled and Google hosts are blocked, so everyone’s sort of happy. But combined with Cloudflare by the use of Google’s captcha service, it gives users an ultimatum if one wants to visit a Cloudflare-encumbered website: either get tracked and sold to spammers, or become an image-clustering monkey working for free for Google. Supposedly Google doesn’t even pay Cloudflare for that: CF are just happy to screw their users in one more way.</p>
<p>Security with Cloudflare is a circus: just look at “<a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/ssl/">Cloudflare One-Click SSL</a>”. Of course they call both X.509 and TLS “SSL”, but there’s much more. The use of non-vulnerable TLS versions is just optional, as the page claims. The “Flexible SSL” mode means “pretend that there is encryption”, making it to look like the connection is safe, while it is plaintext between Cloudflare and an actual server. The “Full SSL” mode is a MitM attack performed by Cloudflare itself. Oh, <a href="https://www.wordfence.com/blog/2017/02/cloudflare-data-leak/">look</a>, “Cloudflare has experienced a data leak over a 5 month period that mixed sensitive data between websites and visitors” – who would have thought! Actively broken security combined with evidently half-assed job turns out to lead to actual leaks. They keep going with a patch and no substantial changes after that, of course.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloudflare#Criticism_and_controversies">criticism listed in Wikipedia</a> doesn’t even cover those, but mentions <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pink_contract">pink contracts</a> and such; indeed, spammers seem to like Cloudflare, as do other scammers.</p>
<p>The only good thing about Cloudflare is that it lists the largest companies that are foolish enough to trust them, so one can use that to find out what to avoid. They tend to list the numbers of clients (“internet properties”, as they call them) as well, in an attempt to exploit at least two common fallacies: appeals <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argument_from_authority">to authority</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argumentum_ad_populum">to the people</a>.</p>
<p>The Wikipedia article mentions that they’ve got some dumb award from TechCrunch. Why don’t we assign awards though? Cloudflare is hereby awarded with our new “fraud of the year” award.</p>
<p>P.S. The public mail service we were using, vivaldi.net, has — in its infinite wisdom — effectively blocked our account as a response to the Cloudflare leak. If you’ve sent anything there in the past year or so, use our updated contacts to resend it.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>OpenTTD</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/games/openttd.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/games/openttd.html</id>
    <published>2017-05-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-05-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info games">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/openttd.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Trains galore</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://binaries.openttd.org/releases/1.7.0/openttd-1.7.0-source.tar.xz">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        GPL 2+
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        May 20, 2017
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://openttd.org/">https://openttd.org/</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/games.html">games</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>Trains are awesome. Everybody loves trains.</p>
<p>With <a href="https://openttd.org/">OpenTTD</a>, one can enjoy train business simulation using a personal computer, with no need of actually getting into train business!</p>
<p>That’s another libre clone<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a> of an older game, with some additional development on top of that. One of the cutting-edge technologies that OpenTTD applies is an additional sensory output: not just you see and hear trains, but you can also smell the burning dirt – supposedly from a video card. Not like there are any fancy graphics, so it can’t be a mere side effect.</p>
<p>Apart from trains, it includes some busses, ships, and aircraft. You build roads, airports, and other stuff, collect money, build more – in a loop. With no way of enjoying what you’ve earned, or any meaningful goal: that’s how good it is at simulating a train entrepreneur’s life.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>More of FOSS clones can be found on <a href="http://osgameclones.com/">osgameclones.com</a>. And <a href="https://libregamewiki.org">libregamewiki.org</a> lists some of those, as well as original games.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Widelands</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/games/widelands.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/games/widelands.html</id>
    <published>2017-05-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-05-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info games">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/widelands.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">A real-time strategy game</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://wl.widelands.org">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        May 19, 2017
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://wl.widelands.org">https://wl.widelands.org</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/games.html">games</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="https://wl.widelands.org/">Widelands</a> is a libre remake — with further development — of an older RTS game Settlers II, focused mainly on building a sustainable and efficient economy, and a little on warfare. There is a variety of resources and buildings, and a player can apply different development strategies.</p>
<p>The first stage of playing it boils down to figuring how it works, what resources and buildings are needed, in what order to build them, etc. Then it’s mostly about perfecting the same strategy. Well, not very different from what one does in most of the other games: acquiring a useless skill, and applying it then.</p>
<p>There’s a lot of maps, some campaigns, and multiplayer is present over both direct connection and a game server.</p>
<p>The game is implemented quite well: as in <a href="/articles/games/wesnoth.html">The Battle for Wesnoth</a>, the graphics here are dated, yet generally it is nice and polished. Though its build process relies on custom shell scripts, but at least they work – so building from sources should not be a problem.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>A fat guy got stuck in a bathtub</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/life/a-fat-guy-got-stuck-in-a-bathtub.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/life/a-fat-guy-got-stuck-in-a-bathtub.html</id>
    <published>2017-02-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info life">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/yagrum-bagarn.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">As this interview did in its review process</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://elderscrolls.wikia.com/wiki/Yagrum_Bagarn">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        February  4, 2017
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/life.html">life</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        breaking news, interview
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>More and more often overweight people are getting stuck in bathtubs<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a>, sometimes <a href="https://imgur.com/gallery/3mD4u">requiring assistance</a> to get released. Surprisingly, both the causes and the mechanisms differ from case to case.</p>
<p>Following the rumors of another overweight guy being stuck in a bathtub, The Asocial interviews the poor fatty himself:</p>
<p><strong>The Asocial (TA)</strong>: Hello, fatty. May I call you that?</p>
<p><strong>Fat Guy (FA)</strong>: I wouldn’t call a person who weights 125 kilograms “fatty”. But I do deem those of a lower weight underweight.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: Interesting world view. How long have you been stuck in the bathtub?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: To be honest, just a few seconds total, but more than once. The whole time I’ve been in control of being stuck, though the second to last didn’t go exactly as planned. Besides, it was rather a suction, I wasn’t literally “stuck”.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: Oh, that is not so bad. But I heard you’ve performed some physical experiments during that time, is that correct?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: More like the other way around: sometimes I’d get stuck while performing physical experiments.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: Could you elaborate on the nature of those experiments?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: Well, I was about to take a bath. Once I’ve sat in the middle of the bathtub, I managed to block the water flow from one half to the other.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: So you could pretend that you’re a human dam while playing with rubber ducks?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: Yes. And I did!</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: But how did you manage to eventually get stuck in there?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: One of my favourite scenarios that I’m playing while pretending to be a dam is an earthquake. So I’ve started to wiggle to emulate it, but that has created a vacuum under my back, and that’s how I got stuck. Then I began researching this effect, and found a position that maximized the vacuum. It even was painful to get unstuck at that point. So I had to get rid of the vacuum, but don’t ask me how.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: Okay, how did you first discover that you can block water flow with your body?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: Once upon a time I’ve sat in the middle of a bathtub, turned the tap on, and behind me there was little water. It was cold, and the water was hot. Then I’ve noticed that the water behind me doesn’t go up, while it does in front of me, and quite fast. Then I figured that I was a dam, and moved forward, what sped up the water level increase rate. Quite an interesting observation that was.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: And what is the purpose of those experiments?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: The question of purpose is rather complex to me, I don’t know the purpose of my actions in general. Except for the basic ones – such as sleeping, eating, getting the food. So I guess it could be best described as plain curiosity. But isn’t it the curiosity that leads us to the most interesting of discoveries? Particularly with one’s own body.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: Probably it is. Is it why you became, hrm, non-underweight?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: No, I’ve chosen to be this way because I’ve got a full-time programming job and a car. A programmer’s salary is high, so I was able to try various foods out of curiosity. I could be doing that virtually all day long.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: I see. By the way, while I’m here, a colleague of mine asked me to find out whether fat shaming really works. What’s your take on that?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: Nope, actually it’s the other way around: I’m proud of my fat and quite happy about it. Particularly while running or camping. By the time when underweight weaklings get exhausted, falling on the ground and freezing, I’m still full of energy; my fat provides that for me.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: Are you eating those weaklings then?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: Also when I’m running a quarter marathon or a half marathon, it’s the same. I’m barely preparing, while they are running a few times per week. For them it’s an offence and humiliation when the fat guy runs on par with them. The last time I’ve got the third place among girls.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: So, contrary to the stereotypes, fatness basically gives you superhuman powers.</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: It just so happened that I didn’t register for the marathon, but my girlfriend did. I decided to support her and ran along with her. But at some point she got tired and gave me her tracker. I’ve managed to get the third place in the women’s marathon, so my girlfriend got a medal, a flask, two 17-litre bottles of water, and 25 hamburgers</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: That’s interesting, and our readers may be curious: how did you get a girlfriend while being fat?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: Well, I was her boss. Or, rather, a team leader.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: And ordered to become your girlfriend?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: Not exactly, though one could say so. We were walking a lot during work hours, and…</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: Okay, stop right there, that gets boring. Have you been stuck in any other places before?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: Yes, I have. Once my girlfriend and I went to a mountain trip. She wanted to see the mountains, but I’ve got stuck on a beach in a cafe. I’ve ordered a large portion of a local dish there, but wasn’t able to eat it all – it was intended to be shared among a company, weighting 1200 grams. But by the end of our vacation I was able to eat it in one go.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: You’ve got stuck there just figuratively speaking, right?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: No, I’d say “mentally”. It’s hard to say “no” to food.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: But what about being stuck physically?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: No, not recalling.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: So that was a new experience for you this time. Are you planning on repeating it in the future?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: Not likely: I’ll have to move out tomorrow, and such bathtubs are uncommon around here.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: Do you know any other non-underweight people who are getting stuck in bathtubs on purpose? Is it like a subculture thing?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: No, but I think they can be forced to.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: “Forced”? Why would you even consider that?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: Technically they are able to, but they are not curious enough about their bodies. So if they were given a purpose, they could definitely do it.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: Any words of encouragement to our readers?</p>
<p><strong>FA</strong>: I don’t think that body fat is any special. Everyone has got enough fat. And if one treats it with care and love, a splendid belly may grow out of it. Or an ass.</p>
<p><strong>TA</strong>: Exciting.</p>
<p>A historical note: fat people predate bathtubs, but they were not taken into account when bathtubs were designed. Some speculate that it’s simply because they’ve required more materials than needed for an average person, but there is a conspiracy theory or two providing alternative explanations.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Comparing to the time when people on average were less obese, or at least to the time when bathtubs did not exist yet.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Top 4 websites</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/top-4-websites.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/top-4-websites.html</id>
    <published>2016-12-21T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-12-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/google.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">The ones that are more popular than Wikipedia</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://www.google.com/images/errors/robot.png">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        December 21, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>Currently there is just 4 websites between Wikipedia and world domination, and we are reviewing those four. Each section begins with a quote from <a href="/articles/internet/alexa-top-500-filtered-again.html">alexa top 500</a>, followed by a list of observations, possibly a comment, and concludes with a more honest description.</p>
<h3 id="google">Google</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>Enables users to search the world’s information, including webpages, images, and videos. Offers unique features and search technology.</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Fails w3 validation (i.e., invalid trash).</li>
<li>Sometimes the website welcomes us with a captcha.</li>
<li>Half of the pages (i.e., one page) is in French, despite web browser locale being English.</li>
</ul>
<p>When attempting to switch to English, or to type anything in the text input field on its main page, an amusing error message appears (the URL is shortened here):</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Your client does not have permission to get URL /sorry/index?continue=https://www.google.fr/… from this server. That’s all we know.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Well, at least it’s in English. Note that there is no permission to get a resource that is an error page according to its URL, not the one we were looking for. As if it wasn’t bad enough, the message also claims that there is no permission to get <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Locator">URL</a>, not the resource it refers to.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Two pages behind a captcha: one is weird, and the other one is to broken as what a supernova is to a confetti cannon.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="youtube">Youtube</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>User-submitted videos with rating, comments, and contests.</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Fails validation.</li>
<li>Lists trashy videos.</li>
<li>Claims to have about 17,000,000 cat videos.</li>
<li>Downloading is not trivial.</li>
<li>Uploading requires to sign in; the login page is slightly broken, but has a link to an account creation page.</li>
<li>The account creation page is also slightly broken, in a different way. Also says that the “qw11112222” password is strong.</li>
<li>Its privacy policy and terms of service describe many different ways in which one would be screwed.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>A file archive limited to videos, with complicated download and no reasonable upload functionality. And with some junk around it.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="facebook">Facebook</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>A social utility that connects people, to keep up with friends, upload photos, share links and videos.</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Fails validation.</li>
<li>Clicking or navigating the website implies agreement with being screwed, so we are not doing that.</li>
<li>Apparently it is useless anyway.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>A closed image gallery or something.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="baidu">Baidu</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>The leading Chinese language search engine, provides “simple and reliable” search experience, strong in Chinese language and multi-media content including MP3 music and movies, the first to offer WAP and PDA-based mobile search in China.</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Won’t load.</li>
</ul>
<p>Well, it explains why “simple and reliable” is quoted.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Plain nothing.</p>
</blockquote>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Blackadder</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/video/blackadder.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/video/blackadder.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info video">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/blackadder.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Guess what? A British sitcom!</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0084988/mediaviewer/rm1930467584">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        November 27, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/video.html">video</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        tv series, history
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blackadder">Blackadder</a> is a four-season-and-a-few-extras historical series, with each season being set in a different (yet recent) century. Some historians believe that it contains real footage, but the mainstream opinion is that it’s just old, yet not old enough to contain that.</p>
<p>It follows the adventures of Edmund Blackadder and his loyal servant Baldrick, along with a few recurring secondary characters. From season to season, the intelligence appears to drift from Baldrick to Blackadder somehow, while Edmund’s social status declines, yet some of the character traits always stay there.</p>
<p><em>As a side note, there is a strange appeal in writing vague nonsense while reviewing something: probably that’s how all those movie summaries come into existence, and not because their authors don’t even care to watch the movies they are writing about.</em></p>
<p>The characters are quite fun, and the cast includes <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rowan_Atkinson">Mr. Bean</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hugh_Laurie">Dr. House</a>, <a href="https://www.gnu.org/fry/">the gNewSense guy</a> who <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephen_Fry#Computing_and_software_freedom">secretly uses</a> <a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/ubuntu-spyware.en.html">Ubuntu</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baldrick">Baldrick</a> (cameo appearance), and some less famous folks.</p>
<p>One of its prominent features is the depiction of the most cunning plans throughout the history: “as cunning as a fox what used to be Professor of Cunning at Oxford University but has moved on and is now working for the U.N. at the High Commission of International Cunning Planning”, for instance. Not all of them have worked out though.</p>
<p>Another nice thing to note about Blackadder is its realism: nobody develops an unlikely friendship there.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Top 500 websites, filtered again</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/alexa-top-500-filtered-again.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/alexa-top-500-filtered-again.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/alexa.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Checking the dynamics</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexa_Internet">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        November  6, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>About a year ago we have <a href="/articles/internet/alexa-top-500-filtered.html">filtered top 500 websites</a> in order to get the trash out of the list, and observe what’s there on the internet. Now we are doing it again, and observing how it changes.</p>
<p>The filter criteria are roughly the same as before: no fraud, social networks, politics, pornography, country-specific and company websites, trading, heavy surveillance, and other kinds of crap. It is not guaranteed to be consistent with the last year’s list, since websites change, perception changes, and we could have missed some of those previously. This time we’ve got 31 website again – 6.2% that are tolerable:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th align="right">#</th>
<th>link</th>
<th>changes</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">5</td>
<td><a href="https://www.wikipedia.org/">wikipedia.org</a></td>
<td>↑ 2</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">24</td>
<td><a href="https://www.reddit.com/">reddit.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 8</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">40</td>
<td><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/">stackoverflow.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">52</td>
<td><a href="https://imgur.com/">imgur.com</a></td>
<td>↓ 6</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">53</td>
<td><a href="https://github.com/">github.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 22</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">55</td>
<td><a href="http://www.imdb.com/">imdb.com</a></td>
<td>↓ 6</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">88</td>
<td><a href="http://www.wikia.com/Wikia">wikia.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">133</td>
<td><a href="https://thepiratebay.org/">thepiratebay.org</a></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">136</td>
<td><a href="https://stackexchange.com/">stackexchange.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 14</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">138</td>
<td><a href="http://www.w3schools.com/">w3schools.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 66</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">151</td>
<td><a href="http://www.deviantart.com/">deviantart.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 47</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">170</td>
<td><a href="https://pages.github.com/">github.io</a></td>
<td>↑ 89</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">195</td>
<td><a href="http://www.wikihow.com/Main-Page">wikihow.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">216</td>
<td><a href="http://www.weather.com/">weather.com</a></td>
<td>↓ 61</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">219</td>
<td><a href="http://extratorrent.cc/">extratorrent.cc</a></td>
<td>↑ 95</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">228</td>
<td><a href="http://www.wordreference.com/">wordreference.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 59</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">231</td>
<td><a href="http://www.nih.gov/">nih.gov</a></td>
<td>↓ 37</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">238</td>
<td><a href="https://www.wikimedia.org/">wikimedia.org</a></td>
<td>same</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">246</td>
<td><a href="https://archive.org/">archive.org</a></td>
<td>↓ 14</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">276</td>
<td><a href="http://www.thesaurus.com/">thesaurus.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 32</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">301</td>
<td><a href="https://rarbg.to/">rarbg.to</a></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">332</td>
<td><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/">goodreads.com</a></td>
<td>↓ 33</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">387</td>
<td><a href="http://dictionary.com/">dictionary.com</a></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">395</td>
<td><a href="https://yts.ag/">yts.ag</a></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">408</td>
<td><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/">sciencedirect.com</a></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">422</td>
<td><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/">kickstarter.com</a></td>
<td>↓ 44</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">424</td>
<td><a href="http://techcrunch.com/">techcrunch.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 68</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">440</td>
<td><a href="https://subscene.com/">subscene.com</a></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">454</td>
<td><a href="http://www.thefreedictionary.com/">thefreedictionary.com</a></td>
<td>↓ 44</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">470</td>
<td><a href="http://azlyrics.com/">azlyrics.com</a></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">479</td>
<td><a href="http://www.webmd.com/">webmd.com</a></td>
<td>↓ 195</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><a href="https://sourceforge.net/">Sourceforget</a> (268) and <a href="https://gizmodo.com/">Gizmodo</a> (488) weren’t included because they are meh. A few torrent trackers got KAT visitors after its <a href="/articles/internet/the-kat-founder-got-arrested.html">takedown</a>.</p>
<p>The Asocial is not in the top yet, and not actually in the ranking at all, but <a href="/articles/comics/search-keywords.html">getting</a> <a href="/articles/comics/went-mainstream.html">there</a>.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Went mainstream</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/went-mainstream.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/went-mainstream.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info comics">
  
  <img src="/images/comics/went-mainstream.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Come and see the censorship inherent in the system!</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        October 23, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/comics.html">comics</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Deep Web in a Nutshell</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/deep-web-in-a-nutshell.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/deep-web-in-a-nutshell.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/onions.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">A quick way to explore Onionland</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Mixed_onions.jpg">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC BY-SA 3.0</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        October 20, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        places
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>As <a href="/articles/internet/a-dark-web-survivor.html">a dark web survivor</a> described <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tor_%28anonymity_network%29#Hidden_services">Onionland</a> about a year ago, it was a mix of the old web, the modern web, and scam. But it evolves, and as it was with clearnet web, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_portal">portals</a> appear that combine all the commonly used services in a single place.</p>
<p>One of such portals is <a href="http://dtt6tdtgroj63iud.onion/">dtt6tdtgroj63iud.onion</a><a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a>, “Deep Web in a Nutshell”, which indeed provides a great outline of deep web: “the dodgy marketplace”, “bitcoin multiplier”, “the abandoned forum”, “the spammy wiki”, “the anonymous uploader to nowhere”, and dozens of its other elaborate up to design details sections are barely distinguishable from the ones you would find on dedicated hidden services, and many of those are nice on their own. Perhaps “<a href="http://dtt6tdtgroj63iud.onion/webdesign/index.html">the rogue web designer</a>” section deserves a highlight, but only as primus inter pares. In addition to that, it includes an illustration of clearnet websites as those can be seen via Tor, and a puzzle. Basically, it is awesome.</p>
<p>Its description sums it up nicely as well:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Why visit lots of dodgy onion sites on the “dark” web, when you can enjoy being bored out of your wits here on this site in perfect safety? Authentic feelings of disappointment guaranteed, or your money back!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>“Deep Web in a Nutshell” is certainly worthwhile to check out if you would like to explore deep web, but don’t have much time for that.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Or use <a href="https://www.onion.to/">Tor2web</a> if you are too lazy to install <a href="https://torproject.org/">Tor</a> – just append “.to” to the domain name: <a href="http://dtt6tdtgroj63iud.onion.to/">dtt6tdtgroj63iud.onion.to</a>.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Human sleep modes</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/life/human-sleep-modes.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/life/human-sleep-modes.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info life">
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">The ways to mess up your sleep</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        October 12, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/life.html">life</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>Sleep is essential to human health and functioning. The need to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleep">sleep</a> is probably one of the most unpleasant things one has to deal with when they have stuff to do, yet the ability to sleep may be one of the most pleasant ones when they don’t. That’s why we take a look at the ways people manage (or mess up) their sleep.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Circadian_rhythm">circadian rhythm</a> is what entangles people into the sleep-wake cycle, the duration of which is usually roughly equal to the time it takes for Earth to complete a full rotation about its axis on average.</p>
<p>Before <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Control_of_fire_by_early_humans">control of fire</a><a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a><a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2"><sup>2</sup></a>, those cycles were all hyped: all the important stuff should have been done during daytime, and it was dark at night before that. Fire was — as they were calling it back then — rad, though people were still into hunting and gathering: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neolithic_Revolution">agricultural revolution</a> happened only around 12,500 years ago, and they didn’t have computers before that. Anyway, now one may have stuff to do all day long, but the rhythms are still there.</p>
<p>Whether naturally or by choice, many people do follow those rhythms, even despite <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insomnia">insomnia</a> and hard time waking up. But some opt for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-24-hour_sleep%E2%80%93wake_disorder">non-24-hour sleep-wake</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irregular_sleep%E2%80%93wake_rhythm">irregular sleep-wake</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biphasic_and_polyphasic_sleep">biphasic/polyphasic sleep</a>, or a combination of those.</p>
<p>In this article, we are going to investigate how various sleep modes affect human lives.</p>
<h2 id="non-24-hour-sleep-wake">Non-24-hour sleep-wake</h2>
<p>That’s a rare disorder that happens when you stop fighting insomnia and using an alarm. Well, at least that’s how it may work if you have <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delayed_sleep_phase_syndrome">DSPD</a> (there’s a rumor that some people don’t have it, so apparently they just go to bed and wake up early, without an alarm or anything). If the cycles are still regular, you still can plan things, just not for any daytime. It only screws regular fixed-time activities, such as an office job.</p>
<p>But let’s be realistic: such a regularity is not exactly what happens if your days are at least slightly different. Usually one day you may get tired more than usual and fall asleep earlier. The next day you may get excited or worried about something, having trouble to sleep, or simply stay longer to finish the stuff you were working on, and the day after that – have an event to attend at a fixed time, setting an alarm, and screwing even that regime. What brings us to the next mode.</p>
<h2 id="irregular-sleep-wake">Irregular sleep-wake</h2>
<p>Wikipedia says that it’s an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invisible_disability">invisible disability</a>, and that “[i]t can create social, familial, and work problems, making it hard for a person to maintain relationships and responsibilities, and may make a person home-bound and isolated”. Though it may be a problem, it’s not a big deal if you are already asocial, except for possible work problems that were already mentioned above.</p>
<p>Although it brings a bunch of other minor inconveniences. Let’s see what happens when you want to visit a regular store: it seems that you have 16 hours of wakefulness, and if the store works for 12 hours per day, there is at least a 4-hour overlap every day. Yet you may sleep up to 12 hours, being sleepy for the last few hours, and taking time to get past <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleep_inertia">sleep inertia</a> when you wake up, as well as to have a breakfast, take a shower, etc – what shrinks the convenient working time. A store may also not be that close to you, so one may add a hour to dress up and get there. All that combined may leave no overlap at all on an arbitrary picked day. Add other things you may want or have to do, and it gets inconvenient rather often: even if you get an overlap, it may not be the time you’d pick if there was a choice. While if you are awake during daytime, most of the time you are awake would work to visit that store.</p>
<p>It’s probably even worse if you order a delivery: since the most responsible people rarely end up being couriers, and delivery companies usually schedule delivery for a range of a few hours, you have to plan being awake for a few hours, possibly a few days ahead. That means that you should maintain at least some kind of a regime during those few days, or adjust the time on the day of delivery.</p>
<p>When you’re trying to adjust your regime to fit the plans, it may involve staying awake longer than you would like to, or trying to sleep when you don’t want to. Both are a waste of time, since you’re neither sleeping nor productive during that, and the latter is the same as one of the downsides of having a regime.</p>
<h2 id="biphasic-and-polyphasic-sleep">Biphasic and polyphasic sleep</h2>
<p>Those are fancy names for daily napping. Napping is generally nice: you may observe that cats do that rather often, and they know what’s good. Napping is common among other animals, too.</p>
<p>But biphasic/polyphasic sleep is more than just occasional napping: it is also called “segmented sleep” and “divided sleep”, implying that it’s about dividing your sleep into a few periods during a cycle.</p>
<p>A bunch of organizations, including NASA and U.S. military, researched the topic, since it’s a nice topic to research. Now there are napping guides, napping tips, napping experts, and napping professionals out there, according to a quick web search. It seems that it is even good for your <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Working_memory">working memory</a>, though it’s not clear how it affects you in a longer term.</p>
<p>Yet it may be quite practical when combined with irregular and non-24-hour sleep: it may be more easily adjustable than a 8-10-hour sleep, since you don’t normally have 16-20 hours without sleep behind you with it, yet the body should still be able to stay awake for those 16-20 hours rather easily. And let’s consider the store situation again: with two equidistant 4-5-hour naps every 24 hours, you get a guaranteed overlap of 7-8 hours, without any adjustment.</p>
<p>Without irregular and non-24-hour sleep, it may even be compatible with a daytime job: working, sleeping, doing other stuff, sleeping again, in a loop.</p>
<p>It may require some effort to get into this mode and to stay in it, since it’s rather easy to stay “late” for a whole day if you’re busy, then fall asleep for a long time, and then get trouble getting a nap after a few hours of being awake. But if you’re willing to put effort into its maintenance, it might be easier to just put that into maintaining a regular 24-hour regime.</p>
<h2 id="hypnotics-and-stimulants">Hypnotics and stimulants</h2>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypnotic">Hypnotics</a> (sleeping pills) and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stimulant">stimulants</a> (caffeine, amphetamine, cocaine, etc) may help to manage your sleep, though the most efficient ones are usually illegal, and even the legal ones have unpleasant side effects when abused.</p>
<h2 id="sleep-deprivation">Sleep deprivation</h2>
<p>According to Wikipedia, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleep_deprivation">sleep deprivation</a> has unpleasant consequences, so it’s not a nice way to get more of free time. Among other things, it may lead to a somewhat interesting condition of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsleep">microsleep</a>.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>It would be awesome to sleep when it’s convenient, and be awake when you have stuff to do. Alas, it’s not exactly how a human body works.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>About 400,000 years ago, when people looked a bit <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homo_erectus">more like monkeys</a> than they do now.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Or maybe even 2.3 million years ago – they’ve only got writing around 5,000 years ago, and started writing lies around that time as well, so it’s hard to know those things for sure.<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Peer review</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/peer-review.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/peer-review.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-08T18:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-08T18:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info comics">
  
  <img src="/images/comics/peer-review.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Reviews are hard</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        October  8, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/comics.html">comics</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
