<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>The Asocial</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://theasocial.com" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>The Asocial</name>
        <email>info@theasocial.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2016-01-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>No reviews</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/no-reviews.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/no-reviews.html</id>
    <published>2016-01-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info comics">
  
  <img src="/images/comics/no-reviews.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Going to publish soon anyway</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        January 17, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/comics.html">comics</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>A tardigrade reproduces</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/nature/tardigrade-30-years-freeze.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/nature/tardigrade-30-years-freeze.html</id>
    <published>2016-01-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info nature">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/santa-tardigrade.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">After being frozen for 30 years</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://imgarcade.com/1/how-big-is-a-tardigrade/">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        January 16, 2016
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/nature.html">nature</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>A Japanese tardigrade named Daisuke Sudo<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a> celebrates the birth of her 14 children. “Not a big deal”, you may think, and indeed it is not a big deal by itself. But Daisuke was frozen in an ice block for 30 years, and reproduced <em>after</em> that.</p>
<p>By the way, did you know that female tardigrades can reproduce on their own? That’s how badass they are.</p>
<p>There’s a bit more about it on <a href="https://ajw.asahi.com/article/sci_tech/science/AJ201601150056">The Asahi Shimbun</a> and <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/blogs-news-from-elsewhere-35323237">BBC</a> websites.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>That’s actually a The Asahi Shimbun writer’s name, while the tardigrade is probably not even Japanese.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Some folks call it a movie review</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/video/sling-blade.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/video/sling-blade.html</id>
    <published>2015-12-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info video">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/sling-blade.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">I reckon I've read more them books than this whole town. Mm-hm.</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        December 23, 2015
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/video.html">video</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        eye-opening, here be spoilers
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>Do not talk to your neighbors. Lock your doors and turn off the lights. Sit tight, prepare yourself for a piece of information that is destined to blow your mind.</p>
<p>Today we will review not just a movie, but the life itself… life of a mentally retarded adult who has spent most part of his life in prison. This small Hollywood masterpiece gives a good insight into the world of an average mid-west hick town and shows the simple life in all its glory.</p>
<p>Karl, convicted at a young age for murdering his mother and her lover, after doing his time finally gets released back into society full of loving and caring individuals. He is a free man now. After many years spent in solidarity where he was sharing his time with books, it seems to be that he turned into the smartest guy in town. Nobody knows who he is and what he’s all about, only the story about a guy who killed his parents with a sling blade goes around in that lil’ ol’ town.</p>
<p>After befriending the second smartest human being in town, a young boy named Frank, he ends up getting a bed at a very hostile and violent home. Back in the 90’s people couldn’t predict well that a man who got convicted for killing his own mother with a blade in an attempt to protect her from what he saw as evil, would ever kill anyone again in an attempt to protect a close person. Thanks to movies like this, even people in mid-west now tend to be more aware of possible patterns in human behavior.</p>
<p>The dialect in the movie portraits with high precision the way frequent Wal-Mart customers communicate with one another. The movie surely teaches people about the right way of taking care of one another, with all that bringing food in bed and sharing same loaf of bread. Just like in the good ol’ days…</p>
<p>The secondary characters are important as well. The most prominent would be the overly social guy who was feeding Karl truly amazing stories about his (mis)fortunate sexual adventures. Although, it might not be the brightest idea to be talking about those things with someone who killed his mother and her lover for having sex together. But it’s a movie, no one in it can predict what’s going to happen in the next ninety minutes or so.</p>
<p>Sometimes Karl appears to be lonesome. But he’s not. He’s got his books and a giant collection of dirty stories that he heard from that strange hospital fellar. Nevertheless, the controlling and emotionally abusive head of the household, Linda, attempts to arrange a blind date for him and the only person who would ever consider getting involved with a mentally impaired person: an overweight female co-worker with social skills of software developer. Things do not seem to be working out since Karl’s posture and, despite the time spent listening to teachings of his “sex guru”, lack of sexual experience, could not overcome the complications of accomplishing intercourse with an overly big lady.</p>
<p>Linda’s boyfriend Doyle, a local rock-star and the only real man in town sometimes acts a bit aggressive. Although such behavior doesn’t seem to surprise or bother anyone in mid-west, her son, who seems to be more out of picture in that nowhere town than the main character, either due to having watched too much television while visiting the local laundromat or the fact of not falling a victim of a curse named general education, one night picks a fight and kicks Linda’s boyfriend out. The boy is most likely a latent homosexual, since he rejects an obvious masculine father figure and prefers to have a retard as someone to look up to. In one of the scenes we’re being shown his lousy attempt of hitting up after a rich girl of his age. It can be clearly seen as a trivial way to forgive himself for own sexuality, therefore blame his choice on lack of success with women at the age of twelve. And no, he did not forget to bring his bubba along with him when he was asking a girl out. Smooth. Despite that, being a stubborn little boy that he is, Frank rejects another father figure, Vaughan, who is 33.7% out of the closet himself. Karl is the father he always wanted to have: who if not the person who killed his family and spent 25 years in jail can teach a young boy how to survive in modern America.</p>
<p>Sling Blade features a few prominent musical tracks, such as the song that Doyle sings for the whole town during his free midnight live performance with his band of five very talented jazz players. This draws a parallel with how similar Doyle’s situation is comparing to Karl’s: one is unable to share his talents because of being unjustly stuck in the wrong place, while the other is unable to open himself up to let people know how much of a great guy he is due to mental impairment.</p>
<p>The story ends with Karl, being unable to compete with Frank’s machismo, decides to get rid of the rival. Ending up back at the same window in his old hospital, listening to another story of his misadventurous story-teller who clearly has no clue about social borders.</p>
<p>This movie teaches us a lot. It teaches us love and ability to forgive, gives us a glimpse at poetry and music of simple American folk. It is definitely not a movie to forget. I am just not certain if I was more happy to discover this magnificent picture or with the fact that I do not live in mid-west.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Lobster</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/video/the-lobster.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/video/the-lobster.html</id>
    <published>2015-12-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info video">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/the-lobster.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">A weird European movie</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3464902/">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        December 19, 2015
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/video.html">video</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lobster">The Lobster</a> is a movie made by a few European countries, but reminds primarily of French movies – such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wrong_%28film%29">Wrong</a>, for instance, though that one is French-American. Somehow their French parts take over all the time: perhaps that’s because they are distinguishably weird and absurd, and look like they are made by kids alone. Plot, sound effects, perhaps even acting – pretty much everything looks that way. They are “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Independent_film">independent</a>” most of the time, tend to be <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Surrealism">surreal</a> and full of metaphors (or just some random stuff that can be interpreted as you wish; metaphors suck), and characters act even more stupid than those in Hollywood horror movies.</p>
<p>This movie is not an exception, and it is also <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dystopia">dystopian</a>, what may make it more or less worthwhile to spend your time on watching. Though its sound effects are really bad and loud, and it is long, as many other boring movies tend to be: most of the 2-hour movies barely have enough of the plot for 10-30 minutes, and many independent films actually are 10-30 minutes long. Probably sometimes they are like “hey, we have more tape left – let’s make it longer”, or “let’s not cut anything, it’s too wasteful to throw away our work”.</p>
<p>One of the best ways to watch it is in background – that is, with another window over it. And definitely without sound, since it is very bad and loud, as was mentioned above. Another option is just to turn it off and remove altogether at the moment when it’ll cross your mind: the movie doesn’t get better as it progresses.</p>
<p>Usually I am seeding a lot, or at least until the 1.0 ratio if a movie is bad, but removed this one as soon as I finished watching it, and felt good about doing so. I feel fooled and robbed of time, so don’t repeat my mistakes.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Let's Encrypt: public beta</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/letsencrypt-public-beta.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/letsencrypt-public-beta.html</id>
    <published>2015-12-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-12-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/letsencrypt.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">A new Certificate Authority</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        December  4, 2015
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        security
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>Yesterday <a href="https://letsencrypt.org/">Let’s Encrypt</a> <a href="https://letsencrypt.org/2015/12/03/entering-public-beta.html">entered public beta</a>, and we have finally got what should have been there from the beginning: a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Certificate_authority">certificate authority</a> that may be tolerable. Although the “authority” part still suggests that it is not a nice thing (see <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anti-authoritarianism">anti-authoritarianism</a>), and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X.509">X.509</a> is all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X.509#Security">messed up</a>, as it was mentioned in our <a href="/articles/computing/using-tor-hidden-services.html">recent Tor article</a>, in some aspects “Let’s Encrypt” is better in comparison to others, and CA authorities in general provide at least some security against non-targeted attacks performed by bigger authorities (governments, that is), or by non-official scam that exploits vulnerabilities introduced by those authorities.</p>
<h2 id="how-it-was-before">How it was before</h2>
<h3 id="fraud">Fraud</h3>
<p>Until now, CAs mostly resembled <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mafia">mafia</a> (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Protection_racket">protection racket</a>), apart from being illegal. Or a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monopoly">monopoly</a> held by a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conglomerate_%28company%29">conglomerate</a>. They basically take money for performing basic computations, often adding some “warranty”. Let’s just take a look at <a href="https://ssl.comodo.com/">this shit</a>; for hundreds of USD the following “advantages” are offered:</p>
<ul>
<li>“Green address bar provides immediate trust and helps customer <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conversion_marketing">conversion</a>”. “Green address bar” — web-centric and non-technical reference, with the most popular browser being assumed — captures pretty much the whole thing, and that’s what server (often website) owners usually pay for: not security, but “customer conversion”. One more reminder that there’s no such things as ethics and morale in those waters.</li>
<li>“2048-bit, highest assurance SSL Certificate, with 99.9% Browser Recognition”. Probably “highest assurance” refers to 2048-bit keys currently being fine in practice: though there is not much overhead with 4096, it is not likely that somebody can forge or bruteforce 2048-bit keys, and if they do – it is rather hard to imagine what they are capable of, and particularly whether 4096-bit keys would help at all. On the other hand, why would they put a vague yet reasonable reference among bullshit? Most likely it’s not that. “SSL Certificate” is not even a thing: they refer to X.509 certificates, used in TLS, as well as in insercure and deprecated SSL. The “99.9%” is obviously pulled out of their ass, which doesn’t require any familiarity with the topic to detect with high accuracy. Though translating from the moron language, “99.9%” means “most” or “uncertain”: just as “50%” means “I don’t know”, and “100%” – “whole”, “all”, or “probably; I’m certain, but I’m ignorant enough to gather that certainty out of thin air”.</li>
<li>“Priority phone support”. Of course, their customers will need it.</li>
<li>“Free <a href="https://www.trustlogo.com/">Comodo TrustLogo</a> for unlimited server licenses”. That’s a nice one: though the “unlimited server licenses” part is not clear, the logo is indeed available for free, and it is just a picture that you put on your website. Marketed with more bullshit, such as “a site seal from a trusted 3rd party can often be the difference between making a sale or not”. It may be confusing for a naive reader, but they indeed list a free picture that you can put anywhere anyway as an advantage of that $400 package, and market that picture as being useful. Somebody thought that it is a good idea – probably the same person who made up the rest of “advantages”. The frightening thing is that probably it indeed was a good idea for their business.</li>
<li>“$1,750,000 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Relying_party">relying party</a> <a href="https://www.comodo.com/repository/docs/SSL_relying_party_warranty.php">warranty</a>”: apparently it is about them warrantying non-violation of their validation procedures, and only covers money transactions, limited by the mentioned sum.</li>
</ul>
<p>And they offer free certificates, too! There are claims such as “Ninety day free SSL Certificate (other CAs offer 30 days maximum.)”; not to mention that it is a lie now, it was a lie for a long time before – even crappy <a href="https://startssl.com/">StartSSL</a> — which requires an outdated TLSv1, which is normally disabled in modern software — used to issue free certificates for a year. Comodo is just the first relevant non-ad result thrown by DDG for “ssl certificates” (you won’t find commercial offers among the first few dozens of results using proper naming), but they are all pretty much the same.</p>
<p>Ironically, CAs exhibit common fraud signs, while they are supposed to protect you from fraud, among other things. Perhaps that’s why they should be “authorities” in order to survive and be legal at all. And that’s just one of the problems with X.509 PKI.</p>
<h3 id="self-signed-certificates">Self-signed certificates</h3>
<p>The problem with self-signed certificates is that most users won’t notice them being forged (unless they have received and installed them manually as “trusted” previously). Some users would mostly see self-signed certificates when attacked by their ISPs: supposedly to enforce censorship without confusing users (and without getting tons of phone calls), those ISPs perform those <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man-in-the-middle_attack">MitM attacks</a> with self-signed certificates, sometimes with default values – in order to show a message, and possibly to intercept data that is supposed to be transmitted over a secure channel. Others will see it while using malicious, hacked, and/or commercial Wi-Fi networks. Self-signed certificates are still better than no encryption at all, unless you get a false sense of safety after seeing one, but generally it implies scam activities, making self-signed certificates only useful in specific cases.</p>
<h2 id="how-it-is-with-le">How it is with LE</h2>
<p>First of all, “Let’s Encrypt” is free, and not a trial/marketing kind of free, which makes it usable for hobby projects and non-essential parts of any projects; it is finally easy to take care of security, and not just “green address bar” for “customer conversion”.</p>
<p>To set certificates with it, you just grab the <a href="https://github.com/letsencrypt/letsencrypt">letsencrypt client</a>, possibly <a href="https://letsencrypt.readthedocs.org/en/latest/">check the documentation</a>, install all the dependencies, and generate a key and a certificate with a single command. It is <em>very</em> easy to use, the certificate gets issued instantly, while in most cases the client takes care of verification for you, providing a few options for that. It also allows you to choose things such as key length, can be set on cron, and apparently updates itself. Neat stuff, which may decrease CA-based fraud and increase overall security over internet in the nearest future.</p>
<p>Though it also has a few issues, as seen from the first glance:</p>
<ul>
<li>Short, 3-month certificate life: it is supposed to force users to automate renewal, but would make less sense for protocols that keep connections for long periods of time, and may be tricky to use for them, if corresponding daemons don’t support certificate reloading without restart.</li>
<li>Weird, enterprise/amateur-software-style installation: that is, ignoring standard ways to install, implementing and using its own scripts to install dependencies, using your package manager.</li>
<li>Plugins to perform very basic tasks, messing with your configs.</li>
<li>Bloated from the beginning, hard to review client, which requires root privileges: currently its repository consists of 482 files, 77992 lines.</li>
<li>Weird choice of languages: Go and Python. Not safe, not fast, not dependency-frugal.</li>
<li>Automated updates, which are supposed to be run from root, executing the updated code at once, and possibly via cron. May easily compromise your server while you are trying to protect connections to it.</li>
<li>Weird name, making it uncomfortable to mention in a sentence.</li>
</ul>
<p>Generally, it takes control over your server for no good reason, making you to hack around in order to gain some control over the process, and is quite web-oriented.</p>
<p>X.509 PKI is still messed up, but “Let’s Encrypt” does not seem to be an outright fraud, as other CAs do.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Tardigrades: foreign DNA</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/nature/tardigrades-foreign-dna.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/nature/tardigrades-foreign-dna.html</id>
    <published>2015-11-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-11-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info nature">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/attack-of-the-tardigrades.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Breaking news</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://ramul.deviantart.com/art/Attack-of-the-tardigrades-143385439">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        November 27, 2015
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/nature.html">nature</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>We wrote <a href="tardigrades.html">how badass tardigrades are</a> before, but the information keeps coming. Do you even know what <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horizontal_gene_transfer">horizontal gene transfer</a> is? Tardigrades not only know what it is, but also use it extensively: currently 17.5% of their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genome">genome</a> is borrowed from other organisms, setting another record by water bears. More than that: bacteria, fungi, plant, whatever – <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNA">DNA</a> is DNA, as the old tardigrade saying states, so they borrow it from everything.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2015/11/18/1510461112">The publication</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proceedings_of_the_National_Academy_of_Sciences_of_the_United_States_of_America">PNAS</a> explains it in more detail, and there is <a href="http://news.meta.com/2015/11/23/waterbear/">a meta.com article</a>. In short, apparently when water bears dry out, their genome may lose integrity, and then it gets ready to borrow missing parts from outside.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Happiness</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/life/happiness.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/life/happiness.html</id>
    <published>2015-11-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-11-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info life">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/wild-cat-and-box.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Is it a myth or reality?</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="http://www.baby-cats.com/">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        November 22, 2015
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/life.html">life</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Happiness">Happiness</a> is a state of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Well-being">well-being</a>, or living a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_good_life">good life</a>. Or something like that; in fact it is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fuzzy_concept">fuzzy concept</a>. But everyone wants to be happy, apparently, and sometimes happiness is described as “that at which everything aims”, and as synonymous with “good”<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a>.</p>
<p>It is said that money don’t matter as much after a certain point, what roughly corresponds to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow%27s_hierarchy_of_needs">Maslow’s hierarchy of needs</a>, though a lot of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychology">psychology</a> is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fraud">fraud</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pseudoscience">pseudoscience</a>, and this particular theory should not be trusted easily. The wikihow’s <a href="http://www.wikihow.com/Be-Happy">“3 Ways to Be Happy”</a> article (don’t get excited: those advices rarely work) points out that people are pretty flexible, and they can adapt to all kinds of things – both good and bad ones. And since happiness seems to go up when something gets better, but to decline afterwards, you are basically doomed to go back back to the base level level of happiness, unless you change stuff around all the time, maintaining those happiness bumps, or unless you live in poverty or something like that. It also suggests that a lot of happiness depends on human interaction, which is unfortunate.</p>
<p>Most of stories (books and movies) which feature happy endings exploit that: they picture how a protagonist achieves happiness (gets out of trouble, achieves something that makes him or her, or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender-specific_and_gender-neutral_pronouns#Summary">whatever pronoun</a> that person prefers, happy), and that’s where the stories should end – since there is gradual decoy right after that. Unless the said happy-ending is suicide or something like that, of course. You may have observed similar effects with toys, hardware, probably relationships, and all the other kinds of nice things which tend to make people happy: initial excitement turns into routine, and then you throw stuff (or people) away.</p>
<p>Being unhappy most of the time may be quite useful for doing some increasingly cool things, since it pushes one to improvement, unless it brings you <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Major_depressive_disorder">depression</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apathy">apathy</a>, or something else along those lines. The latter seems to be similar to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nirvana">Nirvana</a>, which some folks are trying to achieve, though probably it is different somehow – since people don’t seem to strive for apathy. But anyway, when you achieve or learn something, quite soon you stop considering it being that cool, and look for new stuff, or desire for more; in the end you lose, dying unsatisfied (and often <a href="/articles/life/old-age.html">old</a>). That is, unless your last desire was to die, or you were apathetic in the end – but such cases are rarely associated with being happy, though may be associated with being calm (and, well, perhaps that Nirvana thing).</p>
<p>Since the race with ever-growing desires is more or less impossible to win, especially in the constantly changing and worsening world we live in, two strategies are often proposed: to fight those desires, or to use some tricks that are supposed to change your perception of reality – which mostly coincide with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Defence_mechanisms">defence mechanisms</a>. They will not lead to everlasting happiness, but may help to achieve <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contentment">contentment</a>, which may also be pretty nice – though will probably eliminate even occasional happiness. To check how being calm works for you, you can simply wait until you will get sleepy and relaxed (warning: this may be addictive and lead to waste of time). It is trickier with happiness, but if you can’t even think of a way to invoke it – some drugs may assist, or simply <a href="http://www.wikihow.com/Remember-Dreams">remembering your dreams</a> may help: though there is a lot of weird and scary stuff, one may also be genuinely happy in a dream. By the way, <a href="http://www.wikihow.com/Daydream">daydreaming</a> is a weaker alternative.</p>
<p>Perpetual change may work, though it is also quite possible that you will get used to that, and may not always be possible to maintain and desire a perpetual change of positive things.</p>
<p>All in all, prolonged periods of happiness do not seem to be practically achievable, though one may hope for some glimpses of it.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nicomachean_Ethics">Nicomachean Ethics</a> provides an interesting perspective. Though some parts of it may sound rather weird and vague, it is short: paper wasn’t yet invented at the time of writing.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Humour, fun, and laughter</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/life/humour-fun-and-laughter.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/life/humour-fun-and-laughter.html</id>
    <published>2015-11-20T19:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-11-20T19:30:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info life">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/chrysippos.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Cheerful stuff</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Chrysippos_BM_1846.jpg">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        public domain
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        November 20, 2015
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/life.html">life</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>We have decided to write about something cheerful, so here is three topics at once: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humour">humour</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fun">fun</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laughter">laughter</a>. They all may be somewhat mysterious and hard to define, though Wikipedia does that.</p>
<h2 id="humour">Humour</h2>
<p>There are various kinds of humour, and various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theories_of_humor">theories of humour</a>, but it seems to be more or less common in them that unexpected stuff is funny. And it also is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coping_%28psychology%29">coping</a> mechanism, providing you relief. One of the oldest theories states that humour is about feeling superiority: you laugh when you see that somebody is acting stupid or suffers; this theory seems to cover most of the funny things, though it may also depend on personal taste. Also explains why <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Snuff_film">snuff</a> got mixed with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comedy">comedies</a>.</p>
<h2 id="fun">Fun</h2>
<p>As Wikipedia states, fun is an experience, related to enjoyment of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pleasure">pleasure</a>, whereas pleasure may be a lot of things, and often it is something you seek. In many cases it is also easy to link to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evolution">evolution</a>: one usually finds enjoyable the things that helped previous generations to survive. So, basically it is supposed to be fun to survive and prosper.</p>
<h2 id="laughter">Laughter</h2>
<p>One of the versions of the cause of death of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chrysippus">Chrysippus</a> (the guy from the picture, a Greek <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoicism">Stoic</a> philosopher) is that he <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Death_from_laughter">died from laughter</a>. So, one use of laughter is to send something really funny by mail, following the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ted_Kaczynski">Unabomber</a> – just using different technologies. Actually, it seems that he does exactly that now, from the prison: “On May 24, 2012, Kaczynski submitted his current information to the Harvard University alumni association. He listed his eight life sentences as awards, his current occupation as prisoner.”</p>
<p>Seriously though, laughter is mostly a social thing, usually caused by humour or other positive emotions, such as joy. Points out that a group of laughing people understands something in the same way, probably is relaxed (hence friendly), and so on.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smile">Smile</a> appears to be related to laughter, though it is not the same thing.</p>
<p>Note that the interpretation of those differs among cultures: say, websites filled with fake smiles seem to be considered appealing in the webdev culture – especially in its corporate and Indian parts, while in sad ex-USSR countries smiling in public is considered suspicious for obvious reasons: you don’t know what to expect from a person who smiles while being in there. Some of the Asian folks may smile when they are in emotional pain, making it pretty weird.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>That Sugar Film</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/video/that-sugar-film.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/video/that-sugar-film.html</id>
    <published>2015-11-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-11-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info video">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/that-sugar-film.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">A bad documentary film</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        November 20, 2015
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/video.html">video</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        not recommended
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>“<a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3892434/">That sugar film</a>” is a film about dangers of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sugar">sugar</a>, or at least advertised as one. Which may be an interesting topic, but the problem is that it is barely covered in this movie; instead, you get almost 97 minutes of bullshit, which makes you to suspect that it is actually a pro-sugar film, sponsored by sugar companies. Although, assuming that it is not the case, bad examples of pretty much anything can serve another purpose: it is much easier to see how they are trying to trick you when it is not performed professionally. Well, probably it also uses the tricks that are deemed too dumb to be used in professionally made movies, but still – that’s the interesting thing about this movie. It is like observing kids or savages, and then noticing similar behaviours in regular people.</p>
<p>So, the movie begins with a weird guy who complains that his girlfriend made him to abandon sugar, and now he wants to eat a lot of sugar for the sake of an experiment. His girlfriend is also pregnant, which makes it extra-disgusting, but supposedly it is an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Appeal_to_emotion">appeal to emotion</a> – since it seems that some perverts like pregnant women. Or the director, who also played the protagonist, just wanted to get away in addition to eating sugar: like, “I’ll have a good time, which would involve a lot of sugar and some travel, while you suffer from pregnancy. But I’ll film it – so it will be a documentary film, which would make more people to eat grass – that’s what you want, right?”. Would probably be more fun to make such a movie about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alcoholic_beverage">alcohol</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methamphetamine">meth</a>.</p>
<p>The experiment itself is stupid and doesn’t really show much: the guy goes from nearly-zero to really high sugar consumption for two months, and observes how his body gets screwed; perhaps he is a fan of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jackass_%28TV_series%29">Jackass</a>, but he was not nearly as fun.</p>
<p>Most of the movie is pretty boring: it is about him eating sugar, constantly repeating (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ad_nauseam">ad nauseam</a>) how bad sugar is (may remind of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Circular_reasoning">circular reasoning</a>, but there is no reasoning – just an experiment) and how bad he feels (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Appeal_to_pity">appeal to pity</a>, perhaps; there also are scenes where he just feels bad), and eating more. By the end of the movie it is revealed that his body is indeed screwed, but not enough to win <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darwin_Awards">Darwin awards</a>.</p>
<p>There was a whole one researcher in that documentary, a dialogue with whom went like this<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a>:</p>
<p>— Hello. I’m experimenting with my body by eating a lot of sugar after avoiding it, and I feel bad. You tell us that sugar is not that harmful. How would you explain it?</p>
<p>— Hello. Well, pretty much anything is harmful if you consume too much of it, and especially if you are going from one extreme to another: your body gets used to…</p>
<p>— Stop right there, are you getting paid by Coca-Cola?</p>
<p>— Yes, but it does not affect the results, and they can not…</p>
<p>— Ah-ha! So you are working for them! I see now!</p>
<p>Can you tell which <a href="/articles/life/biases-fallacies-and-misconceptions.html">fallacy</a> is that? <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ergo_decedo">Ergo decedo</a>, a type of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ad_hominem">ad hominem</a>, it seems. But the particularly weird thing is that the guy just comes to that researcher, most likely being aware that his research is sponsored by Coca-Cola (or whatever it was), and then invokes the said fallacy. At this point one may think that a lack of sugar makes people retarded (what would also be a fallacy; many jokes involve fallacies, by the way).</p>
<p>In the end the guy stops consuming sugar, and feels ruined – but from this he does not infer that a lack of sugar is harmful, as he did it with sugar two months ago, but does the opposite, of course. And concludes that — surprise! — sugar is bad. With such a methodology, it should be fairly simple to show that fruits and vegetables are extremely unhealthy – not to mention anything else.</p>
<p>Of course, one stupid movie does not imply that sugar is all nice and healthy, or anything serious at all; if you are interested in it, check the corresponding Wikipedia article and go through the links, or just search for it – it should not be hard to find some actual research results. Though the movie also suggests that research is unreliable, apparently implying that they are the only source of truth. And while it is possible, it also appears to be highly unlikely, and is the usual bullshit explanation of made-up things.</p>
<p>The sad part is that such poorly delivered information may have truth in it, but it is hard to tell when it is delivered in such a way; same goes for all the recreational drugs, and a lot of other things. When you see that information about something being harmful is a lie (or vastly exaggregated), it is hard to trust, and one may assume that the thing is in fact harmless. So, it is unclear from this film alone whether sugar is harmful in moderate portions, but the film itself seems to be rather harmful.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>I won’t watch it again, and watched a while ago – so it is a rough paraphrasing from memory; the movie is there for you if you are really interested.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Release delay</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/delay.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/delay.html</id>
    <published>2015-11-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-11-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info comics">
  
  <img src="/images/comics/delay.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Articles being reviewed</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Date
      </th>
      <td>
        November 19, 2015
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/comics.html">comics</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
