<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>The Asocial</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://theasocial.com" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>The Asocial</name>
        <email>info@theasocial.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2018-08-19T19:10:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Domain expiry</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/domain-expiry.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/comics/domain-expiry.html</id>
    <published>2018-08-19T19:10:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-19T19:10:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info comics">
  
  <img src="/images/comics/domain-expiry.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">We're at theasocial.github.io now</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        August 19, 2018
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/comics.html">comics</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Ad unblocking</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/ad-unblocking.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/ad-unblocking.html</id>
    <published>2018-05-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-05-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/abp.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Rage against the users</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        May  5, 2018
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        ads
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>It seems that there’s no end to security-related issues, even if you get tired of and begin to ignore X.509 PKI-related ones, privacy violations by both commercial companies and governments, malware of all kinds, both software and hardware vulnerabilities, data breaches, and all the other common stuff.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghostery">Ghostery</a> used to block trackers while tracking users on its own: a somewhat elegant scam. Recently <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adblock_Plus">Adblock Plus</a> applied a similar approach, but in a bolder form: while blocking the ads, it <a href="https://medium.com/@trybravery/please-stop-using-adblock-but-not-why-you-think-13280e76c8e7">whitelists some ads</a> for a payment, including those of Google.</p>
<p>Fortunately for us, ABP was crap for a while now, so it’s not a great loss: all the cool kids use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UBlock_Origin">uBlock Origin</a> now. Well, except for those from <a href="/articles/internet/internet-in-north-korea.html">North Korea</a>, where most can’t even dream of seeing internet ads. Or from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_in_China">China</a> and—<a href="https://www.article19.org/resources/russia-telegram-block-leads-widespread-assault-freedom-expression-online/">as</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/17/17246150/telegram-russia-ban">of</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/apr/17/russia-blocks-millions-of-ip-addresses-in-battle-against-telegram-app">recently</a>—<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_in_Russia">Russia</a>, where it is challenging to access international ads and/or ad blockers.</p>
<p>Among other recent IT news, which were hard to not notice: <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/03/facebooks-cambridge-analytica-scandal-explained/">Facebook leaks user data to Cambridge Analytica</a>, as well as <a href="https://freedom-to-tinker.com/2018/04/18/no-boundaries-for-facebook-data-third-party-trackers-abuse-facebook-login/">to third-party trackers</a>; <a href="https://doublepulsar.com/hijack-of-amazons-internet-domain-service-used-to-reroute-web-traffic-for-two-hours-unnoticed-3a6f0dda6a6f">Amazon DNS got hijacked for a couple of hours</a>; banks screw up with transfers and lose client accounts; Spectre mitigation patches are still getting issued; all kinds of technologies still get reinvented and reimplemented poorly.</p>
<p>Probably we should limit the infosec news in The Asocial, since it’s basically the same all the time, and people are not likely to cease screwing each other or themselves. It’s an ongoing collective informational self-mutilation: rather shocking, but it’s hard to observe the poor bastards for long, since it’s disgusting if you have enough empathy, or just gets boring otherwise.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>DNS-over-HTTPS</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/dns-over-https.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/dns-over-https.html</id>
    <published>2018-03-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-03-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info computing">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/google.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Another Google spawn</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        March 23, 2018
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/computing.html">computing</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        breaking news, disaster
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>Google has spawned another monster, <a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/public-dns/docs/dns-over-https">DNS over HTTPS</a>. <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/FirefoxNoNightly">Mozilla already experiments on Firefox Nightly users</a> with sending their private data to <a href="/articles/cloudflare.html">Cloudflare</a>, which is another one of early adopters. It’s probably time to start panicking, since that may be the future of DNS.</p>
<h2 id="brief-dns-history">Brief DNS history</h2>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS">DNS</a> usually works on top of UDP, though TCP is used for more important requests, and is defined even in <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1034">RFC 1034</a> from 1987, as well as in <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc883">RFC 883</a> from 1983. It’s pretty simple and minimal, but lacks any means for verification and encryption, allowing a variety of attacks – as early network protocols did in general. Many of those are now used on top of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transport_Layer_Security">TLS</a> instead of TCP, which is a relatively easy transition.</p>
<p>But not DNS.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_Name_System_Security_Extensions">DNSSEC</a> is an ongoing (since 1990s) effort to get DNS records signed by their authors without piggybacking on X.509 PKI (which <a href="/internet/the-trustico-clusterfuck.html">has</a> its own <a href="/internet/letsencrypt-public-beta.html">issues</a>) or anything else. Turns out it’s not such an easy task in the world where we can barely type, transmit, <em>or</em> display text messages, but after a few attempts they’ve got it more or less working on limited deployments. And it still doesn’t provide encryption.</p>
<h2 id="a-new-proposal">A new proposal</h2>
<p>Apparently <a href="systemd.html">Poettering</a> was busy, so Google decided to step in: get the poor thing, and add the needed features, but in the worst way imaginable – if you have a good imagination, that is.</p>
<p>Just adding TLS would be a no-brainer, but Google had to come up with a way to make it more awkward and ads-friendly at once. So they’ve wrapped it in HTTP and in JSON, apparently targeting in-browser JS: no more simple system-wide hosts-based blocking of ads and trackers.</p>
<p>Then they’ve decided to have some fun with the corpse of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model">the OSI model</a>, by engaging into the popular activity of turning the layers inside out, and duplicating their functionality: meet <code>random_padding</code> inside JSON, on top of HTTP, on top of TLS, which by itself can (and should) handle it!</p>
<p>Our <a href="/articles/internet/pimp-my-code-issue-3.html">Pimp My Code</a> team still has a thing or two to learn from those guys.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Trustico clusterfuck</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/the-trustico-clusterfuck.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/the-trustico-clusterfuck.html</id>
    <published>2018-03-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-03-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/trustico.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Yet another X.509 PKI failure</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://www.trustico.co.nz/">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        March  2, 2018
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://www.trustico.co.nz/">https://www.trustico.co.nz/</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        racket
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>As a part of our emerging series of reviews on <a href="the-other-web-of-trust.html">junk with “trust” in its name</a>, as well as those on <a href="startssl-and-friends.html">large-scale X.509 screw-ups</a>, here are the news: Trustico compromised 23 thousand of private keys for X.509 certificates; then compromised them again, and a few more times, until it went public; then blamed DigiCert; then removed that statement.</p>
<p>X.509 PKI is a mess that relies on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Certificate_authority">certificate authorities</a>, which encourages shady schemes and doesn’t work well, yet it’s the best we’ve got so far with a wide adoption. Many CAs take payments for the minuscule calculations they have to perform in order to issue a certificate, sometimes adding an “insurance” that doesn’t quite mean what one may think it means (see also: <a href="/articles/computing/using-tor-hidden-services.html">Using Tor hidden services</a>). It’s pretty bad as it is, but some go further and resell those certificates: they still have to get issued by a CA, of course, but a middleman finds its place even there somehow. It may look ridiculous, but so does every tiny bit of their website, so at least it matches.</p>
<p>Now, what they did is approximately the following, as summed up <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/03/23000-https-certificates-axed-after-ceo-e-mails-private-keys/">by Dan Goodin on Ars Technica</a>, <a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/geofft/status/968937773691539458">by Geoffrey Thomas on Twitter</a>, and throwing in <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sysadmin/comments/816t5f/trustico_website_passing_user_input_directly_to/">a reddit thread</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Made a system featuring, among other things, shell command execution as root on their servers, a lot of marketing crap, and calling X.509 “SSL”.</li>
<li>Have set high prices and added more of marketing bullshit, because it’s not possible to write all that at once without taking a laughing break, and probably consulting a lawyer. The main page alone is hard to read in one go: if you’re used to ditching bullshit, it’s very tempting to close it after every sentence.</li>
<li>Lured the clients (“suckers”, as they are called in the industry) in.</li>
<li>Collected user private keys, which they shouldn’t even have ever accessed. Granted, the users had to be unfamiliar with how it all works in order to hand their keys to Trustico (or generate them with it), but that’s also a prerequirement for choosing something like Trustico, so the coverage was high. That’s basically MitMing the users, as <a href="cloudflare.html">some companies</a> like to do.</li>
<li>Sent those keys by email, apparently intentionally compromising them in an attempt to revoke, and to switch to a different CA (from Symantec to Comodo).</li>
<li>Saw a <a href="https://www.digicert.com/blog/digicert-statement-trustico-certificate-revocation/">DigiCert statement</a>, wrote <a href="https://archive.fo/cpy9b">their own statement</a>, claiming that DigiCert asked them to send the private keys (there’s even something that looks like a quotation).</li>
<li>Removed their own statement, serving an <a href="(https://www.trustico.co.nz/news/2018/symantec-revocation/certificate-replacement.php)">“error page” with prices</a> instead.</li>
</ul>
<p>Apparently switching from Symantec is caused by <a href="https://groups.google.com/a/chromium.org/forum/?_escaped_fragment_=topic/blink-dev/eUAKwjihhBs#!topic/blink-dev/eUAKwjihhBs">Google accusing Symantec of continuous certificate misissuance</a>. Google shouldn’t be in charge of trusted CA certificate distribution, but web browsers can choose where they read trusted CA certificates from, so they can also choose to ship those, and to take control over a large chunk of the infrastructure, but it’s out of scope of this article. Comodo also has a history of screw-ups (and does extensive marketing, of course), but they aren’t getting distrusted yet.</p>
<p>While this system is awkward and broken on virtually every level, they manage to squeeze new levels, and both defraud the users and compromise their keys inside those. Pretty creative, but too bad that most of secure data transfer depends on something so stunningly moronic.</p>
<p>It actually gets tiresome to cover even large-scale screw-ups of (and/or user data abuse by) security-themed companies, since they happen so often: apparently the responsibility, including that for security, is most easily taken either by the entities that are irresponsible and/or clueless, or simply as a scam.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>0 A.D.</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/games/0ad.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/games/0ad.html</id>
    <published>2018-02-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info games">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/0ad.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">A 3D RTS</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://play0ad.com/about/official-logos/">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        February 19, 2018
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://play0ad.com/">https://play0ad.com/</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/games.html">games</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>0 A.D. is an unusually fancy RTS game featuring 3D graphics. Well, “unusually” for libre games.</p>
<p>It’s in development since 2000, still not considered “finished” as of 2018, and warns about bugs and such, but it is pretty usable nevertheless: probably more so than some of the “finished” ones.</p>
<p>The game features 12 ancient civilizations, a few resources, a variety of units and buildings, plenty of maps, single-player and multiplayer modes, different difficulty levels, but no campaigns yet. As with other real-time strategies, the gameplay boils down to learning how to expand fast, but without getting too vulnerable to attacks meantime. It may not sound exciting, probably because it isn’t, but if you’re into RTS, it’s a fine one.</p>
<p>Despite nice graphics and warnings about high resource consumption with larger armies, the resource consumption with the default settings seems to be moderate, apart from quite high disk space requirements (about 1.6 GB of data files).</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The other Web of Trust</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/the-other-web-of-trust.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/the-other-web-of-trust.html</id>
    <published>2018-02-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/the-other-web-of-trust.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Yet another web scam</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Wot_logo_slogan_medium.png">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        registered trademark
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        February 16, 2018
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://www.mywot.com/">https://www.mywot.com/</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        scam
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>Once upon a time, in the early 90s, Phil Zimmermann (the creator of PGP) proposed for people to sign one another’s keys, forming a “web” (a then-hyped term for a graph, cf. World Wide Web), so that a distributed, fault-tolerant, and verifiable key distribution would become possible. It didn’t get adopted widely enough to be useful, because most people don’t know what that is and/or don’t care, and it’s not great for privacy, since the mode of operation usually involves in-person meetings and IDs, but <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Key_signing_party">key signing parties</a> provided at least some socialization for PGP users, so it wasn’t a complete failure in the matter of gaining popularity. That is called “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_of_trust">Web of Trust</a>”, by the way. Its “strong set” (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strongly_connected">strongly connected</a> PGP keys) has a little over 60 thousand keys now, according to <a href="https://pgp.cs.uu.nl/plot/">analysis of the strong set in the PGP web of trust</a>.</p>
<p>In 2007, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WOT_Services">WOT Services</a> (aka MyWOT, aka Web of Trust, too) appeared: with no connection to the actual WOT, of course, and doing something stupid like being an “online reputation system” (like “safe browsing” kind of nonsense that some web browsers provide on their own now). It provided a web browser plugin and had over 100 million downloads by the end of 2013, 140 million currently.</p>
<p>As many other web scams, and following the common theme of marketed “security” software actually being malware, it was involved into <a href="/articles/internet/human-web-trafficking.html">human web trafficking</a>, but nobody cared until the following event:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In November 2016, a German state media investigation found that WOT had secretly collected personal user details and sold or licensed this information to unidentified third-party businesses and entities for data monetization purposes.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Promptly it got thrown out of web browser add-on stores, but added there again in a couple of months, promising that they wouldn’t secretly sell private information to unidentified third parties anymore. They must be trustworthy because there’s “trust” in the name, right?</p>
<p>As Wikipedia also mentions, it has partnerships with other dodgy web enterprises: Mail.ru, Facebook, hpHosts, LegitScript, Panda Security, Phishtank, GlobalSign and TRUSTe. Oh, look, “<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/feb/16/facebook-ordered-stop-collecting-user-data-fines-belgian-court">[Facebook] instructed to delete illegally collected data or face €100m in fines after it loses case over consent and tracking</a>”, as found right after writing the rest of this very article, and they keep spewing marketing crap in response. Be careful with that gang!</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Slack</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/slack.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/slack.html</id>
    <published>2018-02-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info computing">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/slack.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Instant messaging for the computer-illiterate</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Slack_Technologies_Logo.svg">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        public domain
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        February 16, 2018
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://slack.com/">https://slack.com/</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/computing.html">computing</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>Probably everyone knows a person who still refuses to learn those computer things, or a person who already gave up on getting the computer things to work properly, or at least reads news aggregators where those dwell – so the myriad of incompatible and centralized instant messaging protocols controlled by individual companies that milk their users and keep them firmly restrained from escaping shouldn’t be the news<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a>. Some of our readers probably got even pressured into using those; in such a case, contact your local computer user protection services immediately.</p>
<p>As can often be observed, when you take a thing and prefix it with “enterprise”, it gets so much worse: enterprise software companies don’t even try to fool the users, but only focus on those who buy their junk. Some have speculated that if you take an idea that is stupid in the first place, and prefix it with “enterprise”, it will just explode, or implode, or otherwise take care of itself by being too bad to exist. Some curious experimenters decided to find it out, and to everyone’s surprise a stable turd arose out of the Big Junk Collider: meet Slack, an enterprise centralized and incompatible IM! Enhanced vendor lock-in, revolutionized incompatibility, enterprise-grade bullshit, just for $8 per user per month<a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2"><sup>2</sup></a>!</p>
<h2 id="features">Features</h2>
<p>Let’s take a look at the <a href="https://slack.com/features">features</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>“It simplifies communication” (provides chatrooms, to translate it from bullshit-speak): it may seem stupid to list those as a feature, since even IRC provides them, and even video conferencing is not unique to Slack, but they do it.</li>
<li>“It helps everyone find the answers they need” (has a search through the logs): sounds dumb again, but “made more useful with machine learning” hints that they, like, use computers for that. Maybe full-text search, maybe something else – no technical details, of course.</li>
<li>“It streamlines your workflows” (provides a limited extensions API to partially make up for proprietary license): pretty dull still, nothing new there.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s all the reasons they’ve made up to sell Slack. An explanation may be that it is still less broken than the regular client-side software, so let’s look into that.</p>
<h2 id="trying-it-out">Trying it out</h2>
<p>One can <a href="https://slack.com/create#">create a workspace</a> for free, so we’ll do that. The registration is clunky, and it’s hard to pick a name that isn’t taken, but works with JS on, over Tor, and with <a href="https://temp-mail.org/en/">a disposable email</a>. ToS and privacy policy are almost readable, though it’s not far from the usual “your ass belongs to us from now on”.</p>
<p>After the registration, it asks you to spam your friends, so one can just fill some email honeypot addresses there. “Let other people sign up with their verified <span class="citation">@endrix.org</span> email address” is on by default, so there likely to be a lot of “workspaces” into which one can sign up with a public email service.</p>
<p>There are built-in animated tutorials on how to use it, and it’s very laggy (especially if you’re used to real software). Of course using a customized web browser would ruin it, but the default colors are such that they burn your eyes out by making use of a bright white background, and apparently with no way to alter it. Though it features ugly graphical smileys, so it may be useful to burn your eyes out before using it.</p>
<p>Certain buttons just don’t work: some of those say that the feature requires a payment, but others seem to be simply broken, though some of them work after you reload the page. Opening new tabs with middle mouse button doesn’t work; neither does scroll with arrow keys; selection is disabled for some of the elements; generally you are stuck with a few predefined mouse-driven actions they’ve made just for you. Even for those, focus tends to jump to wrong elements.</p>
<p>Slack has extensions and they’re called “apps”. You “install” them into your server-side slack workspace. There are “essential apps”, with Giphy sitting right next to Google Drive. Regular message editing doesn’t extend to attached files, not to mention that in-line images are simply lame.</p>
<p>Ugly as it is, the word on the street is that Slack used to provide at least some occasionally working IRC and XMPP gateways (no federation, but at least a bit of choice and real client software), but <a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201727913-Connect-to-Slack-over-IRC-and-XMPP">gateways are going away</a> in about a month, Google-style.</p>
<p>Basically it is your old <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_chat">web chat</a>, but a rather poor one.</p>
<h2 id="history">History</h2>
<p>Slack, along with Flickr (that broken photo sharing website), was founded by Stewart Butterfield. In both cases he was writing a game, that didn’t work out, but somehow spawned those projects. We wish him luck in the next game project, for it to turn into an actual game without additional spawns.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>See “<a href="https://sameroom.io/chat-timeline.pdf">A Brief History of Chat Services</a>”. Not many of them die, but the rate at which they appear only accelerates so far.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Stop paying and both your data and your infrastructure are gone.<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Meltdown and Spectre</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/meltdown-and-spectre.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/meltdown-and-spectre.html</id>
    <published>2018-01-25T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info computing">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/spectre.min.svg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">A prominent couple of screw-ups</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://spectreattack.com/">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        CC0
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        January 25, 2018
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://spectreattack.com/">https://spectreattack.com/</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/computing.html">computing</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Tags
      </th>
      <td>
        breaking news
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>A couple of serious hardware vulnerabilities got disclosed recently, following <a href="https://www.theregister.co.uk/2018/01/02/intel_cpu_design_flaw/">rumors regarding them coming up</a>, with fancy names that the vulnerabilities get these days. With logos, too. Less fancy names are <a href="http://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=2017-5715">CVE-2017-5715</a> and <a href="http://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=2017-5753">CVE-2017-5753</a> (for Spectre), and <a href="http://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=2017-5754">CVE-2017-5754</a> (for Meltdown).</p>
<p>The vulnerabilities were known for a while, but weren’t disclosed publically, though were reported to Intel, AMD, and ARM on 2017-06-01, as stated in <a href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.de/2018/01/reading-privileged-memory-with-side.html">the Project Zero blog post</a>. And <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2017/12/19/intels-ceo-just-sold-a-lot-of-stock.aspx">Intel’s CEO has sold his stock</a> just before the publication. That would be a good laugh if it didn’t mean that most of the computers are screwed by more than just the backdoors Intel puts into their CPUs, or the occasional vulnerabilities in those backdoors.</p>
<p>The modern processors are pretty sophisticated, incorporating plenty of optimizations such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speculative_execution">speculative execution</a>. The attacks are also interesting, so you may want to read the papers (<a href="https://meltdownattack.com/meltdown.pdf">meltdown.pdf</a>, <a href="https://spectreattack.com/spectre.pdf">spectre.pdf</a>), but briefly – both allow any process on any system and on a lot of the used (i.e., modern, from the current millennium) hardware to read all the data from memory. Commonly used kinds of virtualization don’t help, and even JavaScript in a web browser was successfully used to exploit it, as the Spectre paper claims. Meltdown—which can be mitigated with a kernel patch and only works on Intel and newer ARM processors—allows to read memory at a decent speed, while Spectre seems to be considerably slower, yet harder to mitigate. There’s a <a href="https://gist.github.com/ErikAugust/724d4a969fb2c6ae1bbd7b2a9e3d4bb6">PoC</a> (apparently just copied from the paper though), too.</p>
<p>In order to partially mitigate it, one could update all their systems and disable JavaScript execution (e.g., with <a href="https://noscript.net/">noscript</a> or <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/umatrix/">uMatrix</a>, which are useful even without vulnerabilities like these). But with Spectre around, processes may still be able to see all the memory contents, even across virtual machines (“VPS”, “cloud”, or whatever they are called today). Consequently, the data on services that use such virtual machines got compromised – likely leading to a wave of data breaches.</p>
<p>There’s not much else to do about it now, short of moving everything private to dedicated machines (like RPis or low-end servers if you don’t need a lot of performance) and actually reviewing the software you use. On the bright side, there is a logo to use as a sticker for your vulnerable machines. We could also wait for fixes in newer CPUs; the Intel CEO would probably buy their cheap shares back once that will be about to get announced.</p>
<p>ARM actually published “<a href="https://github.com/ARM-software/speculation-barrier">Speculative Barrier</a>” in an hour after the papers were compiled (see also: <a href="https://developer.arm.com/support/security-update">Arm Processor Security Update</a>); a somewhat similar (and similarly hard-to-apply-to-everything) mitigation technique, <a href="https://support.google.com/faqs/answer/7625886">Retpoline</a>, was presented by Google, not dated; <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/743019/">IBRS patch series</a> were presented by Intel on the following day. Kernel developers were also busy patching things since, but it’s somewhat puzzling why the patches were delayed, and why OS vendors weren’t given a chance to prepare patches before the public disclosure (though a word on the streets is that distribution maintainers were given a couple of months, but for some reason didn’t manage to incorporate patched kernels in that time). Although strange and somewhat related (yet not all that helpful) <a href="HTTP://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16046636">LPTI patching</a> was going on since before the disclosure, and there’s a bit more of the story: “<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/11/16878670/meltdown-spectre-disclosure-embargo-google-microsoft-linux">How an industry-breaking bug stayed secret for seven months — and then leaked out</a>”.</p>
<p>Just a few days after the disclosure, <a href="https://github.com/npm/registry/issues/255">some npm packages disappeared from repositories</a>, providing a good opportunity to infiltrate systems and exploit the newly known vulnerabilities. To make things even more fun, with the hurried patches <a href="https://hothardware.com/news/microsoft-pulls-meltdown-and-spectre-security-patches-that-bricked-pcs-blames-amd">Microsoft has bricked some CPUs</a>, and <a href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/linux/+bug/1742323">Ubuntu has followed it</a>. Another word on the street is that Intel patches also turned out to be buggy, and now they advice the customers to hold off with the updates, though intel.com suggests that “<a href="https://newsroom.intel.com/news/intel-security-issue-update-addressing-reboot-issues/">[e]nd-users should continue to apply updates</a>”. And unlike Linux, MS, and Canonical developers, they knew about it since June – though apparently not the whole story, and didn’t share it with those departments that were able to work on it.</p>
<p>Weeks after the disclosure, not all the common CPUs got microcode updates, and not all the major GNU/Linux distributions have incorporated all the available kernel patches. Linus shouts at Intel folks who try to provide mitigation patches, calling those “<a href="http://lkml.iu.edu/hypermail/linux/kernel/1801.2/04628.html">COMPLETE AND UTTER GARBAGE</a>”.</p>
<p>FreeBSD.org maintains <a href="https://wiki.freebsd.org/SpeculativeExecutionVulnerabilities">a table of architectures by vulnerability</a>.</p>
<p>See also:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-cyber-intel-researcher/how-a-researcher-hacked-his-own-computer-and-found-worst-chip-flaw-idUSKBN1ET1ZR">How a researcher hacked his own computer and found ‘worst’ chip flaw</a></li>
<li><a href="http://kroah.com/log/blog/2018/01/06/meltdown-status/">Meltdown and Spectre Linux Kernel Status</a></li>
<li><a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/742999/">A collection of Meltdown/Spectre postings</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/speed47/spectre-meltdown-checker">Spectre &amp; Meltdown Checker</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Train Driver's View</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/video/train-drivers-view.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/video/train-drivers-view.html</id>
    <published>2017-12-26T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-12-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info video">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/train-drivers-view.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">🚂🚃🚃🚃🚃🚃🚃</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUPn5IEQugMf_JeNJOV9p2A">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        December 26, 2017
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUPn5IEQugMf_JeNJOV9p2A">https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUPn5IEQugMf_JeNJOV9p2A</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/video.html">video</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>As was <a href="/articles/games/openttd.html">stated previously</a>, trains are awesome and everybody loves them. Some of us want to be more like them, too; others just prefer their company to that of meatbags. And some are just in it to watch landscapes, but everyone can enjoy live <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUPn5IEQugMf_JeNJOV9p2A">train driver’s view</a> these days, from multiple trains! No more cut-outs when a meatbag gets in a train’s way, just raw train experience.</p>
<p>There are snowy mountains, lakes, forests, tunnels, bridges, sky, clouds, mist, snow, rain, fellow trains, a whole set of railroad equipment – all at a nice speed, with accelerations, decelerations, and sound. Pretty much everything one needs to effortlessly imagine being a train all day long, every day – without even getting through train driver school (and everyone can’t be a train driver anyway: there are all the dull jobs that have to be done, too; though probably in a fair society it could have been arranged so that everyone had their shift or few as a train driver).</p>
<p>Awesome as it is, there are some technical issues here: for some reason these streams are hosted on youtube, and <code>youtube-dl</code> doesn’t handle live streams, so one has to use a crappy web interface complete with a live chat full of retards (one can try to hide it, but it’ll still blink with parts of messages because of the crappy web UI; <a href="/articles/internet/top-4-websites.html">Google keeps screwing it up</a>) to watch the videos. But that’s a bit less of an issue if you watch those in full screen, as one should for uninterrupted train experience.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Pocket hazing</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/pocket-hazing.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/pocket-hazing.html</id>
    <published>2017-12-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-12-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info computing">
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">Self-abuse with pocket-sized devices</p>
  

  <table>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        December  5, 2017
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/computing.html">computing</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p><a href="/articles/internet/data-breaches.html">Data breaches</a> keep happening as always, and another one has surfaced today: personal data of more than 31 million users <a href="https://mackeepersecurity.com/post/virtual-keyboard-developer-leaked-31-million-of-client-records">got accidently leaked</a> by some smartphone virtual keyboard program (with once again trendy “AI” in its name) developers. It’s not like common desktop systems are great when it comes to security (just a few days ago there was <a href="https://forums.developer.apple.com/thread/79235#277225">another major Apple screwup</a>, which gave root access on Macs to anyone, including remote users via RDP), but pocket-sized devices and applications take it to the next level: with those, it is common to barely ask a user before making large chunks of their private data not-so-private – even as intended behaviour.</p>
<p><del>Web-based services</del>applications for mobile devices (or just “apps” – cool, trendy, short) usually promise to only sell the data to anybody who pays for it, so that must be fine. Occasionally they leak it, of course, but that happens.</p>
<p>As if it wasn’t bad enough, mobile software tends to require permissions to access much more of personal data than one may expect that software to ever need: usually it doesn’t make sense for the problem a program solves, but apparently users got used to it anyway. It was the case here as well, so among the leaked data there are locations, contact books, emails, some social networks data, and other stuff like that. Basically, it was malware even before the leak, but so is every other smartphone (or tablet) program. Well, not literally “every other”: most of them are.</p>
<p>One may think that it’s some sort of informational exhibitionism, but people in general are not as cunning or subtle to do it that way.</p>
<p>It only leaves about one rational explanation: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hazing">hazing</a>. Apparently the easiest way to socialize these days is to use a pocket-sized computer device with a touchscreen and “apps” on it, so those get used for instant initiation in the form of “activities involving harassment, abuse, or humiliation”. Easy, automated, and builds solidarity.</p>
<p>One may miss the good old days when a poor bastard sitting in a pile of human excrements for initiation at least didn’t compromise bits of others’ private data by leaking their contact book, but the progress is inevitable.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Top 50 websites, filtered</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/alexa-top-50-filtered.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/internet/alexa-top-50-filtered.html</id>
    <published>2017-11-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info internet">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/alexa.jpg" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">50, not 500</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexa_Internet">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        November 24, 2017
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/internet.html">internet</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>Following our traditional November filtered collections of the most popular websites (“<a href="/articles/internet/alexa-top-500-filtered.html">Top 500 websites, filtered</a>”, “<a href="/articles/internet/alexa-top-500-filtered-again.html">Top 500 websites, filtered again</a>”), this is one more list – though this time we’ve got only 50 websites, because Alexa doesn’t show more anymore. Times are tough, information is expensive.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th align="right">#</th>
<th>link</th>
<th>changes</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">5</td>
<td><a href="https://www.wikipedia.org/">wikipedia.org</a></td>
<td>same</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">8</td>
<td><a href="https://www.reddit.com/">reddit.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td align="right">46</td>
<td><a href="https://imgur.com/">imgur.com</a></td>
<td>↑ 6</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td align="right">50</td>
<td><a href="https://wordpress.com/">wordpress.com</a></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The previously filtered out Wordpress was added, because we have plenty of space left anyway – and perhaps it’s not more trashy than reddit and imgur.</p>
<p>Maybe we should switch to filtering <a href="https://github.com/search?q=stars:%3E1&amp;s=stars&amp;type=Repositories">most starred github repositories</a>, since those are also full of junk, but still open.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Trisquel</title>
    <link href="http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/trisquel.html" />
    <id>http://theasocial.com/articles/computing/trisquel.html</id>
    <published>2017-11-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info computing">
  
  <img src="/images/articles/trisquel.png" alt=""/>
  
  
  
  <p class="abstract">An offspring of bickering</p>
  

  <table>
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image source
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://trisquel.info/en/wiki/logo">Image source</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Image license
      </th>
      <td>
        Rubén Rodríguez Pérez's trademark or something
      </td>
    </tr>
    


    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Article date
      </th>
      <td>
        November 24, 2017
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        URI
      </th>
      <td>
        <a href="https://trisquel.info/">https://trisquel.info/</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    <tr>
      <th>
        Category
      </th>
      <td>
        <a class="cat" href="/categories/computing.html">computing</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    
    
  </table>
</div>

<div id="article">
  <p>Laptops usually are pre-assembled, since it is tricky to build one yourself out of generic components available in a hardware store; there currently are projects that try to change it, but this article is not about them. Since the laptops usually are pre-assembled, it almost makes sense to sell them with pre-installed operating systems, what became a tradition. After all, it’s easy, makes the laptop operational at once, and there’s a whole Minix complete with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intel_Active_Management_Technology#Known_vulnerabilities_and_exploits">backdoors and vulnerabilities</a> right inside CPUs – why not to add a user-usable system on top of that? Though it adds extra cost to install MS Windows, and some users want other systems anyway, so some manufacturers went as far as to install systems such as DOS (in this millenium, that is): not actually usable, but just to install something there.</p>
<p>And so it goes: FSF’s “<a href="https://www.fsf.org/resources/hw/endorsement/respects-your-freedom">Respects Your Freedom</a>” computer hardware certification program is generally fine with those Intel backdoors, as long as there’s no way to get rid of them, but demands the rest to be free (libre) software. Well, fine, still making the best out of the situation, but the funny part is ahead. Debian is a rather old, popular, large, and notably libre (no blobs in the kernel, no proprietary software or firmware in the default repositories) GNU/Linux distribution – an obvious default choice, one may think. Not for FSF! Debian wiki <em>mentions</em> how to enable non-free repositories (as if newbie users actually read through the docs: the naive bastards still hope that software would work out of the box), which are even hosted on the same servers as the default ones – apparently contaminating the free software or something. That’s the reason enough for FSF to <a href="https://www.gnu.org/distros/common-distros.en.html#Debian">count Debian as non-free</a>. Meantime, Debian puts GNU documentation into non-free repositories, since, well, <a href="https://www.debian.org/vote/2006/vote_001">they</a> <a href="https://people.debian.org/~srivasta/Position_Statement.xhtml">see</a> it as non-free. That’s how largest free software projects do collaborate, without even bringing Linux into the picture.</p>
<p>This way, <a href="https://www.gnu.org/distros/free-distros.html">GNU’s endorsed distributions</a> get restricted mostly to awkward and uncommon ones, and FSF requires those to be installed on computers that want to get a RYF badge and promotion. If the FLOSS-friendly computer manufacturers were a single large entity, we’d probably have them boycotting both FSF and Debian as non-free by now, and using FreeBSD or something – judging by how well these projects get together when they have a reasonable choice.</p>
<p>And finally, Trisquel is one of the things that grew out of it.</p>
<p>It is derived from Ubuntu (which is derived from Debian, as you may know already, and as many other now-abandoned distributions were), sponsored by <a href="https://www.thinkpenguin.com/">ThinkPenguin</a>, its <a href="https://trisquel.info/en/download">most recent release</a> is from 2014-03-11, its <a href="https://listas.trisquel.info/pipermail/trisquel-security/">security announcements mailing list</a> is silent since 2014, while Trisquel-devel seems to be filled with rather strange messages – although Trisquel-users is active, so apparently it’s still alive, at least in the hearts of its users.</p>
<p>Apart from being a filler system, akin to DOS in that, Trisquel actually tries to follow the FSF spirit and to be nice: apparently it provides some accessibility features, possibly going further than those of Debian and Ubuntu (why would it mention them otherwise?). So the blind kids could get traumatized by the Python backtraces from its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sugar_(software)">Sugar</a> edition just as any others do, using screen readers. Well, probably – I haven’t tried either.</p>
<p>It’s rather ironic how those smaller accessibility-oriented user-friendly distributions can easily require more experience and effort than the more common ones, because you’re mostly on your own if something goes wrong, and the issue is hidden under layers and layers of poorly documented GUI and wrappers, or quite often just lays inside those layers. And it’s rarely debugging-oriented, on top of that. But FSF still prefers to expose new users to that, rather than to a distribution that doesn’t make it hard enough for users to install non-free packages.</p>
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
